<ns0:speak xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/10/synthesis" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="1.1" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/2001/10/synthesis">
<p><s>to enter or to board a vehicle</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get in/to get on. Comment: To get in is used for cars; to get on is used for all other forms of transportation. Examples: It's easiest to get in the car from the driver's side. The door on the other side doesn't work well. I always get on the bus to work at 34th Street."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to leave or to descend from a vehicle</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get out of/to get off. Comment: To get out of is used for cars; to get off is used for all other forms of transportation. Examples: Why don't we stop and get out of the car for a while? Helen got off the train at the 42nd Street terminal."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to place on oneself (usually said of clothes) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to put on. Examples: Mary put on her coat and left the room. Put your hat on before you leave the house.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to remove (usually said of clothes) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to take off. Examples: John took off his jacket as he entered the office. Take your sweater off. The room is very warm.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to telephone (also: to give someone a call) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to call up. Comment: To call can be used instead of to call up, as in the first example below. Examples: I forgot to call up Mr. Jones yesterday. I'd better call him now. Call me up tomorrow, Jane. We'll arrange a time to have lunch together. I promise to give you a call as soon as I arrive in New York."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to start or cause to function (also: to switch on) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to turn on. Examples: Please turn on the light; it's too dark in here. Do you know who turned the air conditioning on?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to cause to stop functioning (also: to switch off, to shut off) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to turn off. Comment: Turn on and turn off, as well as their related forms, are used for things that flow, such as electricity, water, gas, etc. Examples: Please turn off the light when you leave the room. Are you really listening to the radio, or should I turn it off?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>very soon; immediately (also: at once)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"right away. Examples: Dad says that dinner will be ready right away, so we'd better wash our hands and set the table. Tell Will to come to my office right away. I must see him immediately. Stop playing that loud music at once!"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to lift from the floor, table, etc., with one's fingers (S)"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to pick up. Examples: Harry picked up the newspaper that was on the front doorstep. Could you pick your toy up before someone falls over it?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>eventually, after a period of time</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"sooner or later. Examples: If you study English seriously, sooner or later you'll become fluent. I'm too tired to do my homework now; I'm sure I'll do it sooner or later."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to arise, to rise from a bed; to make someone arise (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get up. Comment: For the last definition a noun phrase must separate the verb and particle. Examples: Carla gets up at seven o'clock every morning. At what time should we get the children up tomorrow?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>in the beginning, originally</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>at first. Examples: At first English was difficult for him, but later he made great progress. I thought at first that it was Sheila calling, but then I realized that it was Betty.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to wear formal clothes, to dress very nicely</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to dress up. Examples: We should definitely dress up to go to the theater. You don't have to dress up for Mike's party."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>finally, after a long time</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"at last. Examples: We waited for hours and then the train arrived at last. Now that I am sixteen, at last I can drive my parents' car."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>as is the general case, as is typical</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"as usual. Examples: George is late for class as usual. This seems to happen every day. As usual, Dora received first prize in the swimming contest. It's the third consecutive year that she has won."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>get information about, to determine (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to find out. Comment: This idiom is separable only when a pronoun is used, as in the second example. Examples: Will you please try to find out what time the airplane arrives? I'll call right now to find it out."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"give one's attention to; to watch"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to look at. Examples: The teacher told us to look at the blackboard and not at our books. I like to walk along a country road at night and look at the stars.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to try to find, to search for</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to look for. Comment: An adverb phrase such as all over can be put between the verb and preposition, as in the second example, however, the idiom cannot be separated by a noun or pronoun. Examples: He's spent over an hour looking for the pen that he lost. So there you are! We've looked all over for you."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>acceptable, fine; yes, okay</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>all right. Comment: This idiom can also be spelled alright in informal usage. Examples: He said that it would be all right to wait in her office until she returned. Do you want me to turn off the TV? Alright, if you insist.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>all the time, from the beginning (without change)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"all along. Examples: She knew all along that we'd never agree with his plan. You're smiling! Did you know all along that I'd give you a birthday present?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>gradually, slowly (also: step by step)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"little by little. Examples: Karen's health seems to be improving little by little. If you study regularly each day, step by step your vocabulary will increase."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to make very weary due to difficult conditions or hard effort (also: to wear out) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to tire out. Examples: The hot weather tired out the runners in the marathon. Does studying for final exams wear you out? It makes me feel worn out!
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to ask for a response from; to visit (also: to drop in on)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to call on. Examples: Jose didn't know the answer when the teacher called on him. Last night several friends called on us at our home. Why don't we drop in on Sally a little later?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"don't be concerned about it; ignore what was just said"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"never mind. Examples: When he spilled his drink on my coat, I said, ""Never mind. It needs to be cleaned anyway."" So you weren't listening to me again. Never mind; it wasn't important."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to choose, to select (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to pick out. Examples: Ann picked out a good book to give to her brother as a graduation gift. Johnny, if you want me to buy you a toy, then pick one out now.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to do without rush, not to hurry</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take one's (my, his, your, etc.) time. Comment: This idiom is often used in the imperative form. (See the first example) Examples: There's no need to hurry doing those exercises. Take your time. William never works rapidly. He always takes his time in everything that he does."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to discuss or consider a situation with others (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to talk over. Examples: We talked over Carla's plan to install an air conditioner in the room, but we couldn't reach a decision. Before I accepted the new job offer, I talked the matter over with my wife."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to place oneself in a flat position, to recline</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to lie down. Examples: If you are tired, why don't you lie down for an hour or so? The doctor says that Grace must lie down and rest for a short time every afternoon."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to rise from a sitting or lying position (also: to get up)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to stand up. Examples: When the president entered the room, everyone stood up. Suzy, stop rolling around on the floor; get up now.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be seated (also: to take a seat)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to sit down. Examples: We sat down on the park bench and watched the children play. There aren't any more chairs, but you can take a seat on the floor."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>the entire day, week, month, year</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"all (day, week, month, year) long. Examples: I've been working on my income tax forms all day long. I've hardly had time to eat. It's been raining all week long. We haven't seen the sun since last Monday."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>alone, without assistance</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>by oneself. Examples: Francis translated that French novel by himself. No one helped him. Paula likes to walk through the woods by herself, but her brother prefers to walk with a companion.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>for a reason, deliberately</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"on purpose. Comment: This idiom is usually used when someone does something wrong or unfair. Examples: Do you think that she didn't come to the meeting on purpose? It was no accident that he broke my glasses. He did it on purpose."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to associate or work well with; to succeed or manage in doing (also: to get on with someone or something)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get along with someone (something). Examples: Terry isn't getting along with her new roommate; they argue constantly. How are you getting on with your studies?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be of importance (to), to affect</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to make a difference (to someone). Comment: This idiom is often used with adjectives to show the degree of importance. Examples: It makes a big difference to me whether he likes the food I serve. Does it make any difference to you where we go for dinner? No, it doesn't make any difference. It makes no difference to Lisa either."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to remove, to extract (S); to go on a date with (S) (also: to go out with)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take out. Examples: Students, take out your books and open them to page twelve. Did you take Sue out last night? No, she couldn't go out with me."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be involved in, to participate in (also: to be in on)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take part in. Examples: Martin was sick and could not take part in the meeting yesterday. I didn't want to be in on their argument, so I remained silent."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to any degree (also: in the least)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"at all. Comment: This idiom is used with the negative to add emphasis to a statement. Examples: Larry isn't at all shy about expressing his opinions. When I asked Donna whether she was tired, she said, ""Not in the least. I'm full of energy."""
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to locate information in a directory, dictionary, book, etc. (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to look up. Examples: Ellen suggested that we look up Lee's telephone number in the directory. Students should try to understand the meaning of a new word from context before looking the word up in the dictionary."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to serve in a store or restaurant</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to wait on someone. Examples: A very pleasant young clerk waited on me in that shop. The restaurant waitress asked us, ""Has anyone waited on you yet?"""
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>a minimum of, no fewer (or less) than</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>at least. Examples: I spend at least two hours every night on my studies. Mike claims that he drinks at least a quart of water every day.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>until now, until the present time (also: up to now, as of yet)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>so far. Comment: This idiom is usually used with the present perfect tense. Examples: So far, this year has been excellent for business. I hope that the good luck continues. How many idioms have we studied in this book up to now? As of yet, we have not had an answer from him.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to go for a walk, stroll, hike, etc.</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take a walk, stroll, hike, etc.. Comment: A stroll involves slow, easy walking; a hike involves serious, strenuous walking. Examples: Last evening we took a walk around the park. It's a fine day. Would you like to take a stroll along Mason Boulevard? Let's take a hike up Cowles Mountain this afternoon."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to go on a journey, to travel</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take a trip (to). Examples: I'm so busy at work that I have no time to take a trip. During the summer holidays, the Thompsons took a trip to Europe."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to wear clothes to check the style or fit before buying (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to try on. Examples: He tried on several suits before he picked out a blue one. Why don't you try these shoes on next?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to consider carefully before deciding (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to think over. Examples: I'd like to think over your offer first. Then can we talk it over tomorrow? You don't have to give me your decision now. Think it over for a while."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to occur, to happen according to plan</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take place. Examples: The regular meetings of the committee take place in Constitution Hall. I thought that the celebration was taking place at John's house."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to remove from sight, to put in the proper place (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to put away. Examples: Please put away your papers before you open the test booklet. John put the notepad away in his desk when he was finished with it.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be careful or cautious (also: to watch out)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to look out. Comment: Both of these idioms can occur with the preposition for. Examples: ""Look out!"" Jeffrey cried as his friend almost stepped in a big hole in the ground. Look out for reckless drivers whenever you cross the street. Small children should always watch out for strangers offering candy."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to exchange greetings by clasping hands</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to shake hands. Examples: When people meet for the first time, they usually shake hands. The student warmly shook hands with his old professor.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to return (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get back. Examples: Mr. Harris got back from his business trip to Chicago this morning. Could you get the children back home by five o'clock?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become sick with a cold of the nose or throat</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to catch cold. Examples: If you go out in the rain, you will surely catch cold. How did she ever catch cold in such warm weather?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to recover from an illness; to accept a loss or sorrow</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get over. Examples: It took me over a month to get over my cold, but I'm finally well now. It seems that Mr. Mason will never get over the death of his wife."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to reach a decision, to decide finally</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to make up one's (my, his, your, etc.) mind. Examples: Sally is considering several colleges to attend, but she hasn't made up her mind yet. When are you going to make up your mind about your vacation plans?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to alter one's decision or opinion"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to change one's (my, his, your, etc.) mind. Examples: We have changed our minds and are going to Canada instead of California this summer. Matthew has changed his mind several times about buying a new car."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>temporarily (also: for now)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"for the time being. Examples: For the time being, Janet is working as a waitress, but she really hopes to become an actress soon. We're living in an apartment for now, but soon we'll be looking for a house to buy."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>permanently, forever</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"for good. Examples: Ruth has returned to Canada for good. She won't ever live in the United States again. Are you finished with school for good, or will you continue your studies some day?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to cancel (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to call off. Examples: The referee called off the soccer game because of the darkness. The president called the meeting off because she had to leave town.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to postpone (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to put off. Examples: Many students put off doing their assignments until the last minute. Let's put the party off until next weekend, okay?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>hurried, rushed (also: in a rush)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"in a hurry. Examples: Alex seems in a hurry; he must be late for his train again. She's always in a rush in the morning to get the kids to school."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>not feeling well, sick</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>under the weather. Examples: John stayed home from work because he was feeling under the weather. When you catch cold, you feel under the weather.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to place clothes on a hook or hanger (S); to replace the receiver on the phone at the end of a conversation (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to hang up. Examples: Would you like me to hang up your coat for you in the closet? The operator told me to hang the phone up and call the number again.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to trust someone in time of need (also: to depend on)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to count on. Examples: I can count on my parents to help me in an emergency. Don't depend on Frank to lend you any money; he doesn't have any."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become friendly with others</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to make friends (with). Examples: Patricia is a shy girl and doesn't make friends easily. During the cruise Ronald made friends with almost everyone on the ship."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>not in working condition</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"out of order. Examples: The elevator was out of order, so we had to walk to the tenth floor of the building. We couldn't use the soft drink machine because it was out of order."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be able to do something special; to arrive at a place, such as home, work, etc.</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get to. Comment: For the second definition, do not use the preposition to with the words home or there. Examples: The children got to stay up late and watch a good movie for the family. I missed the bus and couldn't get to the office until ten o'clock. When are you planning to get home tonight?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>not frequent, unusual, rare</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>few and far between. Examples: The times that our children get to stay up late are few and far between. Airplane travel is very safe because accidents are few and far between.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to examine, to inspect closely (also: to go over, to read over, to check over) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to look over. Comment: Go over is different from the other forms because it is not separable. Examples: I want to look my homework over again before I give it to the teacher. The politician went over his speech before the important presentation. You should never sign any legal paper without checking it over first.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to have free time, not to have to work (also: to take time off (S))</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to have (time) off. Comment: The related form (S) to take time off is used when someone makes a decision to have free time, sometimes when others might not agree with the decision. Examples: Every morning the company workers have time off for a coffee break. Several workers took the afternoon off to go to a baseball game.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to happen; to resume, to continue (also: to keep on)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to go on. Examples: Many people gathered near the accident to see what was going on. I didn't mean to interrupt you. Please go on. The speaker kept on talking even though most of the audience had left."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>extinguish, to cause to stop functioning (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to put out. Comment: To put out has the same meaning as to turn off (Lesson 1) for a light fixture. Examples: No smoking is allowed in here. Please put out your cigarette. The fire fighters worked hard to put the brush fire out. Please put out the light before you leave. Okay, I'll put it out."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>suddenly, without warning (also: all at once)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"all of a sudden. Examples: All of a sudden Ed appeared at the door. We weren't expecting him to drop by. All at once Millie got up and left the house without any explanation."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to show, to indicate, to bring to one's attention (S)"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to point out. Examples: What important buildings did the tour guide point out to you? The teacher pointed out the mistakes in my composition. A friend pointed the famous actor out to me.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to expire, to be finished</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be up. Comment: This idiom is used only with the word time as the subject. Examples: ""The time is up,"" the teacher said at the end of the test period. We have to leave the tennis court because our hour is up; some other people want to use it now."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be finished, to end (also: to be through)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to be over. Comment: This idiom is used for activities and events. Examples: After the dance was over, we all went to a restaurant. The meeting was through ten minutes earlier than everyone expected.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>exactly at the correct time, punctually</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>on time. Examples: I thought that Margaret would arrive late, but she was right on time. Did you get to work on time this morning, or did rush hour traffic delay you?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>before the time necessary to do something</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>in time to (do something). Examples: We entered the theater just in time to see the beginning of the movie. The truck was not able to stop in time to prevent an accident.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become better, worse, etc.</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get better (worse, etc.). Examples: Heather has been sick for a month, but now she is getting better. This medicine isn't helping me. Instead of getting better, I'm getting worse."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become sick, well, tired, busy, wet, etc.</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to get sick (well, tired, busy, wet, etc.). Comment: This idiom consists of a combination of get and various adjectives. Examples: Gerald got sick last week and has been in bed since that time. Every afternoon I get very hungry, so I eat a snack.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>should, ought to, be advisable to</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"had better (do something). Comment: This idiom is most often used in contracted form (I'd better). Examples: I think you'd better speak to Mr. White right away about this matter. The doctor told the patient that he'd better go home and rest."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>prefer to (also: would just as soon (do something) as (do something else))</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>would rather (do something). Examples: Would you rather have the appointment this Friday or next Monday? I would just as soon go for a walk as watch TV right now.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to stop working for the rest of the day/night</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to call it a day/night. Examples: Herb tried to repair his car engine all morning before he called it a day and went fishing. We've been working hard on this project all evening; let's call it a night."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to solve, to find a solution (S); to understand (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to figure out. Examples: How long did it take you to figure out the answer to the math problem? I was never able to figure it out.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to have a (good or bad) opinion of</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to think of. Comment: This idiom is often used in the negative or with adjectives such as much and highly. Examples: I don't think much of him as a baseball player; he's a slow runner and a poor hitter. James thinks highly of his new boss, who is a kind and helpful person."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be at the moment of doing something, to be ready</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be about to do something. Comment: This idiom is often used with the adverb just. Examples: I was just about to leave when you telephoned. Oh, hi, John. We're just about to eat dinner."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to move or face in the opposite direction (S); to completely change the condition of (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to turn around. Examples: The man turned his car around and drove back the way he came. The company has been very successful since the new business manager was able to turn it around.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to alternate, to change people while doing something</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to take turns (doing something). Examples: During the trip, Darlene and I took turns driving so that neither of us would tire out. I have to make sure that my two sons take turns playing the video game.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to look at and listen to someone while they are speaking, to concentrate</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to pay attention (to). Examples: Please pay attention to me while I'm speaking to you! You'll have to pay more attention in class if you want to get a good grade."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to review something in order to refresh one's memory"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to brush up on something. Examples: Before I traveled to Mexico, I brushed up on my Spanish; I haven't practiced it since high school. In order to take that advanced mathematics class, Sidney will have to brush up on his algebra."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>repeatedly (also: time after time, time and again)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"over and over (again). Examples: The actress studied her lines in the movie over and over until she knew them well. Children have difficulty remembering rules, so it's often necessary to repeat them over and over again. Time and again I have to remind Bobby to put on his seatbelt in the car."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to use something until it has no value or worth anymore, to make useless through wear (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to wear out. Examples: When I wear out these shoes, I'll have to buy some that last longer. What do you do with your clothes after you wear them out?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to discard, to dispose of (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to throw away. Examples: I generally throw away my clothes when I wear them out. Don't throw the magazines away; I haven't read them yet."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to begin to love</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to fall in love. Comment: This idiom is used with the expression at first sight to indicate a sudden interest in love. Examples: Ben and Sal fell in love in high school, and got married after graduation. Have you ever fallen in love at first sight?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to stop functioning; to stop burning; to leave home or work (also: to step out)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to go out. Examples: The lights went out all over the city because of an electrical problem. The campers didn't have to put out the fire because it went out by itself. Gary isn't here right now; he went out to the store for a moment. I have to step out of the office briefly to pick up a newspaper."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>impossible, not feasible</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"out of the question. Examples: Stephen told Deborah that it was out of the question for her to borrow his new car. Don't expect me to do that again. It's absolutely out of the question."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to have some connection with or relationship to</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to have to do with. Examples: Ralph insisted that he had nothing to do with breaking the window. What does your suggestion have to do with our problem?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to arise from sleep, to awaken (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to wake up. Comment: Compare wake up and get up (Lesson 1) as used in the first example. Examples: Marge woke up this morning very early, but she did not get up until about ten o'clock. My alarm clock wakes me up at the same time every day."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to manage, to have responsibility for</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to be in charge (of something). Examples: Jane is in charge of the office while Mrs. Haig is on a business trip. Who is in charge of arrangements for the dance next week?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>just after, when</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"as soon as. Examples: As soon as it started to snow, the children ran outside with big smiles on their faces. I'm busy now, but I'll meet you as soon as I've finished this work."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to communicate with, to contact</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get in touch with. Examples: You can get in touch with him by calling the Burma Hotel. I've been trying all morning to get in touch with Miss Peters, but her phone is always busy."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to enjoy oneself</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to have a good time. Examples: We all had a good time at the class reunion last night. Did you have a good time at the park? I really enjoyed it.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>very quickly, rapidly</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"in no time. Comment: This idiom can be used with the idiom at all to add emphasis to the certainty of the statement. Examples: Mac said that he'd be ready to leave in no time. We thought that the meeting would take two hours, but it was over in no time at all."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to reduce, to lessen (also: to cut back on)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to cut down on. Examples: In order to lose weight, you have to cut down on your intake of sugar. The doctor told me to cut back on exercise until my back injury heals.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>many</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>quite a few. Examples: Quite a few students were absent yesterday; in fact, more than half of them were not there. We did not expect many people to attend the affair, but quite a few of our friends actually came.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>formerly did, had the habit of</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>used to. Comment: This idiom is used to indicate a past situation, action, or habit that does not exist in the present. The idiom is always followed by a simple verb form. Examples: I used to live in New York, but I moved to California two years ago. Kim used to smoke cigarettes, but she stopped the habit last month.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>be accustomed to</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be used to. Comment: This idiom refers to a situation, action, or habit that continues in the present. The idiom is always followed by a noun or gerund phrase. Examples: He is used to this climate now, so the changes in temperature do not affect him much. I am used to studying in the library, so it's difficult for me to study at home now."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become used to, to become adjusted to</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get used (to something). Comment: This idiom describes the process of change that allows someone to be used to a situation, action, or habit. Examples: It took Yoshiko a long time to get used to the food that her American host family served her. Mark can't seem to get used to wearing contact lenses; recently he's been wearing his glasses a lot."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>in a backward and forward motion</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>back and forth. Examples: The restless lion kept pacing back and forth along the front of its cage. Grandmother finds it relaxing to sit in her rocking chair and move back and forth.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be sure, to ascertain (also: to make certain (of))</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to make sure. Examples: Please make sure that you turn off the radio before you go out. Could you make certain of the time? I don't want to miss that TV show."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>occasionally, sometimes (also: now and again, at times, from time to time, off and on, once in a while)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"now and then. Comment: Both now and then and once in a while can be preceded by the adjective every. Another idiom with the same meaning and form is every so often. Examples: I don't see him very often, but (every) now and then we arrange to have lunch together. Gary gets a cold (every) once in a while even though he takes good care of himself. Every so often my brother and I get together for a camping trip. I like to sleep late in the morning from time to time."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to eliminate, to remove; to discard, to throw away</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to get rid of. Examples: Jerry tried hard to get rid of the stain on his shirt, but he never succeeded. The stain was so bad that Jerry finally had to get rid of his shirt.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>every second (one), alternate (ones)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>every other (one). Examples: I play tennis with my father every other Saturday, so I usually play twice a month. There were twenty problems in the exercise, but the teacher told us only to do every other one. Actually, doing ten problems was difficult enough.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to match, to compare well in color or design; to date, to accompany (also: to go out with)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to go with. Comment: For the first definition, adverbs such as well and poorly are often used. Examples: That striped shirt goes well with the gray pants, but the pants go poorly with those leather shoes. Eda went with Richard for about six months, but now she is going out with a new boyfriend.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>excellent, superb</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>first-rate. Examples: The food served in that four-star restaurant is truly first-rate. The Beverly Hills Hotel provides first-rate service to its guests.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to originate from</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to come from. Comment: This idiom is commonly used in discussion of one's home town, state, or country. Examples: What country in South America does she come from? She comes from Peru. I just learned that he really comes from Florida, not Texas. Where did this package come from? The mail carrier brought it."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to travel a sufficient distance at a reasonable speed</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to make good time. Comment: The adjective excellent can also be used. Examples: On our last trip, it rained the entire time, so we didn't make good time. We made excellent time on our trip to Florida; it only took eighteen hours."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to stir or shake well (S); to confuse, to bewilder (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to mix up. Comment: For the second definition, the passive forms to be mixed up or to get mixed up are often used. Examples: You should mix up the ingredients well before you put them in the pan. The teacher's poor explanation really mixed the students up. The students think it's their fault that they are mixed up so often."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to give attention or time to (also: to attend to, to see to)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to see about. Examples: Who is going to see about getting us a larger room for the meeting? I'll see to arranging music for the wedding if you attend to the entertainment."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to do, to succeed, to progress</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to make out. Examples: Charlie didn't make out very well on his final examinations. He may have to repeat one or more classes. How did Rachelle make out on her acting audition in Hollywood yesterday?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>by memorizing</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>by heart. Examples: He knows many passages from Shakespeare by heart. Do you know all the idioms you have studied in this book by heart?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>not to enter, not allow to enter (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to keep out. Examples: There was a large sign outside the door that said, ""Danger! Keep out!"" I've told you to keep the dog out of the house."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to stay at a distance (from) (S); to avoid use of (also: stay away from)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to keep away (from). Examples: Please be sure to keep the children away from the street! The signs on the burned-out house said, ""Keep Away! Danger Zone."" It's important for your health to stay away from dangerous drugs."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to criticize, to complain about something</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to find fault with. Examples: It is very easy to find fault with the work of others, but more difficult to accept criticism of one's own work. Mrs. Johnson is always finding fault with her children, but they really try to please their mother."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be responsible for deciding; to be doing as a regular activity</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be up to. Comment: The second definition is most often used in a question as a form of greeting. Examples: I don't care whether we go to the reception or not. It's up to you. Hi, George. I haven't seen you in a while. What have you been up to?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>uncomfortable or worried in a situation</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>ill at ease. Examples: Speaking in front of a large audience makes many people feel ill at ease. My wife and I were ill at ease because our daughter was late coming home from a date.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to revise, to do again (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to do over. Comment: A noun or pronoun must separate the two parts of this idiom. Examples: You'd better do the letter over because it is written so poorly. Jose made so many mistakes in his homework that the teacher made him do it over."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to investigate, to examine carefully (also: to check into)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to look into. Examples: The police are looking into the matter of the stolen computers. The congressional committee will check into the financial dealings of the government contractor.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to grasp, to grip with the hands</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to take hold of. Examples: You should take hold of the railing as you go down those steep stairs. The blind man took hold of my arm as I led him across the street.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to finish, to complete</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get through doing something, to get through with something. Comment: This idiom is followed either by the -ing form of a verb (a gerund) or by the preposition with. Examples: I didn't get through studying last night until almost eleven o'clock. At what time does your wife get through with work every day?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>from this time into the future</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"from now on. Examples: Mr. Lee's doctor told him to cut down on eating fatty foods from now on, or else he might suffer heart disease. I'm sorry that I dropped by at a bad time. From now on I'll call you first."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to keep or maintain a record of; to remember the location of</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to keep track of. Examples: Steve keeps track of all the long-distance telephone calls related to his business that he makes from his home. With seven small children, how do the Wilsons keep track of all of them?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be greatly affected by a strong feeling (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to be carried away (by, with). Comment: This idiom can also be used with get instead of be. Examples: Paula and Leanne were carried away by the sad movie that they saw together. James got carried away with anger when his roommate crashed his new car into a telephone pole.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>modern, current, timely</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>up to date. Comment: Hyphens (-) separate the parts of this idiom when it precedes a noun form, as in the third example. The verb to update derives from this idiom. Examples: The president insisted that the company bring its aging equipment up to date. This catalog is not up to date. It was published several years ago. The news program gave an up-to-date account of the nuclear accident. The newscaster said that he would update the news report every half hour.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>not modern, not current, not timely; no longer available in published form</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"out of date. Comment: Again, hyphens separate the parts of this idiom when it precedes a noun form as in the second example. The passive verb to be outdated derives from this idiom. Examples: Many people buy new cars when their old cars become out of date. I don't know why Gene likes to wear out-of-date clothing. His clothes are so outdated that even his girlfriend hesitates to be seen with him. This book can't be ordered any more because it is out of date."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to inflate, to fill with air (S); to explode, to destroy (or be destroyed) by explosion (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to blow up. Examples: Daddy, could you please blow up this balloon for me? When the airplane crashed into the ground, it blew up immediately. The military had to blow the missile up in midair when it started to go the wrong way.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to begin to burn</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to catch fire. Examples: Don't stand too close to the gas stove. Your clothes may catch fire. No one seems to know how the old building caught fire."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to burn slowly, but completely (usually said of candles); to destroy completely by fire (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to burn down. Examples: There was a large amount of wax on the table where the candles had burned down. The fire spread so quickly that the firefighters could not prevent the whole block of buildings from burning down.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to destroy completely by fire (S); to make angry or very annoyed (S) (also to tick off)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to burn up. Comment: To burn up and to burn down (previous idiom) share the same definition but also have different definitions. Examples: She didn't want anyone to see the letter, so she burned it up and threw the ashes away. It really burns me up that he borrowed my car without asking me first. Mike got ticked off that his friends never offered to help him move to his new apartment. He had to do everything himself."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to stop functioning because of overuse; to make tired from too much work (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to burn out. Examples: This light bulb has burned out. Could you get another one? Studying all day for my final exams has really burned me out.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to succeed</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to make good. Examples: He is a hard worker, and I'm sure that he will make good in that new job. Alma has always made good in everything that she has done."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be clear and logical</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"stands to reason. Comment: This idiom is almost always used with the pronoun subject it and is followed by a that clause. Examples: It stands to reason that a person without experience cannot do the work as well as an experienced one. It stands to reason that he isn't going to pass the course if he never studies."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become widespread suddenly</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to break out. Examples: An epidemic of measles broke out in Chicago this past week. If a nuclear war ever breaks out, it is unlikely that many people will survive. The news says that a large fire has broken out in a huge chemical plant.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>regarding, concerning (also: as to)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"as for. Examples: As for the money, we will simply have to borrow some more from the bank. There is no doubt as to her intelligence; she's the smartest one in the class."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to pity, to feel compassion for (also: to take pity on)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to feel sorry for. Examples: Don't you feel sorry for someone who has to work the night shift? I helped drive Pierre around when he broke his foot because I took pity on him."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to stop functioning</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to break down. Comment: Compare this idiom with to burn out in Lesson 12. To burn out means that electrical equipment becomes hot from overuse and stops functioning. To break down means that something stops functioning mechanically, whether from overuse or not. Examples: I just bought my new car yesterday and already it has broken down. The elevator broke down, so we walked all the way up to the top floor.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become or result; to appear, to attend (also: to come out)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to turn out. Comment: The noun form turnout derives from the second definition of the idiom. Examples: Most parents wonder how their children will turn out as adults. Hundreds of people came out for the demonstration against new taxes. What was the turnout for the public hearing on the education reforms?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>rarely, infrequently</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>once in a blue moon. Examples: Snow falls on the city of San Diego, California, once in a blue moon. Once in a blue moon my wife and I eat at a very expensive restaurant.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to stop trying; to stop a bad habit (S); to surrender (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to give up. Examples: I'm sure that you can accomplish this task. Don't give up yet! If you give up smoking now, you can certainly live a longer life. The soldiers gave themselves up in the face of stronger enemy forces."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to cancel by marking with a horizontal line (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to cross out. Examples: The teacher crossed out several incorrect words in Tanya's composition. I crossed the last line out of my letter because it had the wrong tone to it."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>not to appreciate fully (S); to assume to be true without giving much thought (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take for granted. Comment: A noun or pronoun often follows the verb take. Examples: John took his wife for granted until once when he was very sick and needed her constant attention for a week. He spoke English so well that I took it for granted he was an American. He took for granted that I wasn't American because I spoke English so poorly!"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to consider a fact while evaluating a situation (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take something into account. Comment: Again, a noun or pronoun often follows the verb take. Examples: The judge took the prisoner's young age into account before sentencing him to three months in jail. Educators should take into account the cultural backgrounds of students when planning a school curriculum."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to clarify, to explain (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to make clear. Examples: Please make clear that he should never act so impolitely again. The supervisor made it clear to the workers that they had to increase their productivity.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>clearly stated, definite, apparent</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"clear-cut. Examples: The president's message was clear-cut: the company had to reduce personnel immediately. Professor Larsen is well known for his interesting and clear-cut presentations."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be wearing (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to have on. Examples: How do you like the hat which Grace has on today? When Sally came into the room, I had nothing on except my shorts.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to regain consciousness; to equal, to amount to</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to come to. Examples: At first they thought that the man was dead, but soon he came to. The bill for groceries at the supermarket came to fifty dollars.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to require; to request, to urge</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to call for. Examples: This cake recipe calls for some baking soda, but we don't have any. The members of Congress called for new laws to regulate the banking industry."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to eat at home/to eat in a restaurant</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to eat in/to eat out. Examples: I feel too tired to go out for dinner. Let's eat in again tonight. When you eat out, what restaurant do you generally go to?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>predictable, known beforehand; boring</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>cut and dried. Examples: The results of the national election were rather cut and dried; the Republicans won easily. A job on a factory assembly line is certainly cut and dried.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to watch, to supervise, to protect (also: to take care of, to keep an eye on)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to look after. Examples: Grandma will look after the baby while we go to the lecture. Who is going to take care of your house plants while you are away? I'd appreciate it if you'd keep an eye on my car while I'm in the store."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to have the desire to, to want to consider</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to feel like. Comment: This idiom is usually followed by a gerund (the -ing form of a verb used as a noun). Examples: I don't feel like studying tonight. Let's go to a basketball game. I feel like taking a long walk. Would you like to go with me?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>finally, absolutely</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"once and for all. Examples: My daughter told her boyfriend once and for all that she wouldn't date him anymore. Once and for all, John has quit smoking cigarettes."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to receive news or information from</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to hear from. Comment: To hear from is used for receiving a letter, telephone call, etc., from a person or organization. Examples: I don't hear from my brother very often since he moved to Chicago. Have you heard from the company about that new job?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to know about, to be familiar with; to consider</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to hear of. Comment: The second definition is always used in the negative. Examples: When I asked for directions to Mill Street, the police officer said that she had never heard of it. Byron strongly disagreed with my request by saying, ""I won't hear of it!"""
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to laugh at, to joke about</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to make fun of. Examples: They are making fun of Carla's new hair style. Don't you think that it's really strange? Don't make fun of Jose's English. He's doing the best he can."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become reality, to prove to be correct</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to come true. Examples: The weatherman's forecast for today's weather certainly came true. Everything that the economists predicted about the increased cost of living has come true."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>really, actually (also: in fact)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"as a matter of fact. Examples: Hans thinks he knows English well but, as a matter of fact, he speaks very poorly. I didn't say that. In fact, I said quite the opposite."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to arrange matters the way one wants (especially when someone else doesn't want the same way) (also: to get one's way)"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to have one's way. Examples: My brother always wants to have his way, but this time our parents said that we could do what I wanted. If Sheila doesn't get her way, she becomes very angry."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to expect or anticipate with pleasure</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to look forward to. Comment: This idiom can be followed by a regular noun or a gerund. Examples: We're greatly looking forward to our vacation in Mexico. Margaret never looks forward to going to work."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>with the inside facing the outside</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>inside out. Examples: Someone should tell little Bobby that his shirt is inside out. The high winds ruined the umbrella by blowing it inside out.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>with the upper side turned toward the lower side</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>upside down. Examples: The accident caused one car to turn upside down, its wheels spinning in the air. One of the students was only pretending to read her textbook; the teacher could see that the book was actually upside down.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to write answers in (S); to inform, to tell (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to fill in. Comment: For the second definition, the idiom can be followed by the preposition on and the information that someone is told. Examples: You should be careful to fill in the blanks on the registration form correctly. Barry was absent from the meeting, so I'd better fill him in. Has anyone filled the boss in on the latest public relations disaster?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to complete a form (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to fill out. Comment: This idiom is very similar to the first definition above. To fill in refers to completing various parts of a form, while to fill out refers to completing a form as one whole item. Examples: Every prospective employee must fill out an application by giving name, address, previous jobs, etc. The teenager had some trouble filling the forms out by himself, so his mother helped him.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to use well, to profit from; to use another person's weaknesses to gain what one wants"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take advantage of. Examples: I took advantage of my neighbor's superior skill at tennis to improve my own ability at the game. Teddy is such a small, weak child that his friends take advantage of him all the time. They take advantage of him by demanding money and making him do things for them."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>regardless of</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"no matter. Comment: This idiom is a shortened form of it doesn't matter. It is followed by a question word such as how, where, when, who, etc. Examples: No matter how much money he spends on his clothes, he never looks well dressed. No matter where that escaped prisoner tries to hide, the police will find him sooner or later."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to begin to do or study, to undertake (S); to occupy space, time, or energy (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take up. Examples: After today's exam, the class will be ready to take up the last chapter in the book. The piano takes up too much space in our living room. However, it would take too much time up to move it right now; so we'd better wait until later."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to consult someone about an important matter (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take up with. Comment: The important matter follows the verb take, while the person consulted follows with. Examples: Can I take the problem up with you right now? It's quite urgent. I can't help you with this matter. You'll have to take it up with the manager."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to resemble a parent or close relative (for physical appearance only, also: to look like)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to take after. Examples: Which of your parents do you take after the most? Sam looks like his father, but he takes after his mother in personality.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>eventually, after a long period of time</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"in the long run. Comment: This idiom is similar in meaning to sooner or later (Lesson 1). The difference is that in the long run refers to a more extended period of time. Examples: In the long run, the synthetic weave in this carpet will wear better than the woolen one. You won't have to replace it so soon. If you work hard at your marriage, you'll find out that, in the long run, your spouse can be your best friend in life."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>having contact</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"be in touch (with). Examples: James will be in touch with us soon to relay the details of the plan. I certainly enjoyed seeing you again after all these years. Let's be sure to keep in touch."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>not having contact; not having knowledge of</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>out of touch with. Examples: Marge and I had been out of touch for years, but then suddenly she called me up the other day. Larry has been so busy that he seems out of touch with world events.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>alert, cautious</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"on one's toes. Comment: This idiom is usually used with the verbs stay and keep. Examples: It's important for all the players on a soccer team to stay on their toes. We'd better keep on our toes while we're walking along the dark portions of this street."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to make progress; to manage to live in a certain state of health</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to get along. Examples: Juan is getting along very well in his English studies. How is Mr. Richards getting along after his long illness?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>partially deaf, not able to hear well</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"hard of hearing. Examples: You'll have to speak a little louder. Mrs. Evans is hard of hearing. Please don't shout. I'm not hard of hearing. Listening to loud music too much can make you hard of hearing."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to agree, to concur</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to see eye to eye (on something/with somebody). Examples: I'm glad that we see eye to eye on the matter of the conference location. A husband and wife don't always see eye to eye with each other, but a good marriage can survive small disagreements."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be considering, to be thinking (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to have in mind. Examples: I don't want to see a movie now. I have in mind going to the park. It's up to you what we eat tonight. Do you have anything in mind?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to remember, not to forget (S) (also: to bear in mind)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to keep in mind. Examples: Please keep in mind that you promised to call Stan around noon. I didn't know that Paula doesn't like vegetables. We should bear that in mind next time we invite her for dinner."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>this one time, for only one time</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>for once. Examples: For once I was able to win a game of golf against Steve, who is a much better player than I am. Dad, for once would you please let me drive the new car?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to explode, to sound as an alarm; to leave suddenly without explanation</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to go off. Examples: The accident happened when a box of firecrackers went off accidentally. For what time did you set the alarm clock to go off tomorrow morning? Vince went off without saying good-bye to anybody; I hope he wasn't angry."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to outgrow, to become too old for, to be a result of</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to grow out of. Examples: He still bites his nails now and then, but soon he'll grow out of the habit. The need for the salary committee grew out of worker dissatisfaction with the pay scale."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to do the best that one can in a poor situation</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to make the best of. Examples: If we can't find a larger apartment soon, we'll just have to make the best of it right here. Even though the Martinez family is having financial problems, they make the best of everything by enjoying the simple pleasures of life."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to shorten by cutting the ends (S); to disconnect or stop suddenly (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to cut off. Examples: The rope was two feet longer than we needed, so we cut off the extra length. The operator cut our long-distance phone conversation off after two minutes.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to remove by cutting (S); to stop doing something (S) (for the second definition, also: to knock it off)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to cut out. Comment: For the second definition, the idiom is usually separated by the pronoun it. Examples: The child likes to cut out pictures from the newspaper and to paste them in a notebook. He kept bothering her, so finally she told him to cut it out. However, he wouldn't knock it off until her larger brother appeared."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to explode, to go flat (for tires); to extinguish by blowing (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to blow out. Examples: On our trip to Colorado, one of the car tires blew out when it hit a large hole in the road. Little Joey wasn't able to blow all the candles out, so his big sister helped him."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to happen to (a missing object or person)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to become of. Comment: This idiom is always used in a clause beginning with what. Examples: What has become of my pencil? I had it ten minutes ago, but now I can't find it. I wondered what became of you. I looked around the shopping center for two hours, but I couldn't find you at all."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to close for a period of time (S); to be quiet, to stop talking</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to shut up. Comment: The second definition of this idiom is impolite in formal situations. Examples: During the hurricane, all the store owners shut their shops up. Bob's sister told him to shut up and not say anything more about it. The student got into big trouble for telling his teacher to shut up."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to have, to possess</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"have got. Examples: Curtis has got a bad cold. He's sneezing and coughing a lot. How much money have you got with you right now?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>must (also: have to)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"have got to. Examples: She has got to go to Chicago today to sign the contract papers. I have to be back home by two o'clock or my wife will feel ill at ease."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to maintain the same speed or rate as</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to keep up with. Examples: Frieda works so fast that no one in the office can keep up with her. You'll have to walk more slowly. I can't keep up with you."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>however, in contrast</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>on the other hand. Examples: Democracies provide people many freedoms and privileges. On the other hand, democracies suffer many serious problems such as crime and unemployment. My sister takes after my father in appearance. On the other hand, I take after my mother.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to reduce in brightness or volume (S); to reject, to refuse (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to turn down. Examples: Please turn down the radio for me. It's too loud while I'm studying. Laverne wanted to join the military but the recruiting officer turned her application down because Laverne is hard of hearing in one ear."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>divided into two equal parts</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"fifty-fifty. Examples: Let's go fifty-fifty on the cost of a new rug for our apartment. The political candidate has a fifty-fifty chance of winning the election."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>gradually to prepare something for use that is new and stiff (S); to interrupt (for the second definition, also: to cut in)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to break in. Examples: It is best to break a new car in by driving it slowly for the first few hundred miles. While Carrie and I were talking, Bill broke in to tell me about a telephone call. Peter, it's very impolite to cut in like that while others are speaking."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>a hopeless case, a person or situation having no hope of positive change</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"a lost cause. Examples: It seems that Charles will never listen to our advice. I suppose it's a lost cause. The police searched for the missing girl for two weeks, but finally gave it up as a lost cause. Children who have committed several crimes as teenagers and show no sorrow about their actions are generally lost causes."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>mainly, especially</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"above all. Examples: Above all, don't mention the matter to Gerard; he's the last person we should tell. Sheila does well in all her school subjects, but above all in mathematics. Her math scores are always over 95 percent."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>survive or exist without something (also: to go without)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to do without. Examples: With prices so high now, I'll have to do without a new suit this year. As a traveling salesperson, Monica can't do without a car. It's a shame that so many poor people in the world have to go without basic necessities of life such as nutritious food and suitable shelter."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>in the order of; on the authority of</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>according to. Examples: The students on the football team were ranked according to height, from shortest to tallest. According to my dictionary, you are using that word in your essay incorrectly.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be certain to do something, to be sure to do something</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be bound to do something. Comment: This idiom is used when the occurrence of an event seems inevitable or unavoidable. Examples: We are bound to be late if you don't hurry up. With the economy improving now, their business is bound to make more money this year."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>without doubt (also: for certain)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"for sure. Examples: In the dark, I couldn't tell for sure whether it was Polly or Sarah who drove by. I know for certain that Gene will move back to Washington next month."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to perceive or understand as (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take for. Comment: This idiom is usually used when someone is mistakenly perceived. A noun or pronoun must separate the idiom. Examples: Because of his strong, muscular body, I took him for a professional athlete. As it turns out, he doesn't play any professional sports. What do you take me for  a fool? I don't believe what you're saying at all."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to test, to use during a trial period (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to try out. Examples: You can try out the new car before you decide to buy it. I can let you try the computer out for a few days before you make a decision.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to destroy by making flat, to demolish (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to tear down. Examples: The construction company had to tear down the old hotel in order to build a new office building. The owners had to tear the house down after it burned down in a fire.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to rip into small pieces (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to tear up. Examples: Deidre tore up the letter angrily and threw all the pieces into the trash can. He told the lawyer to tear the old contract up and then to prepare a new one.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be appreciated or accepted</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to go over. Comment: This idiom is usually followed by the adverb well. (In Lesson 6 this idiom has the meaning to review, as in the second sentence of the second example below.) Examples: The teacher's organized lessons always go over well with her students. The comedian's jokes weren't going over well; the audience wasn't laughing much at all. I think that the comedian should go over his material more carefully before each act."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to exhaust the supply of, not to have more of</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to run out of. Examples: We ran out of gas right in the middle of the main street in town. It's dangerous to run out of water if you are in an isolated area."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>basically, fundamentally</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"at heart. Comment: This idiom is used to describe the true character of a person. Examples: James sometimes seems quite unfriendly, but at heart he's a good person. The Fares often don't see eye to eye, but at heart they both love each other very much."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>ready to, just going to</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"be about to do smth. Examples: We were about to leave the house when the phone rang. I'm sorry that I broke in. What were you about to say?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to accept as a responsibility or task</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to bite off. Comment: This idiom is often used when one accepts more responsibility than one can handle alone. It is usually used in the form to bite off more than one can chew. Examples: When I accepted the position of chairman, I didn't realize how much I was biting off. When James registered for 18 units in his last semester at college, he bit off more than he could chew."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to distinguish between (also: to pick apart, to tell from) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to tell apart. Examples: The two brothers look so much alike that few people can tell them apart. That copy machine is so good that I can't pick the photocopy and the original apart. Most new cars are very similar in appearance. It's almost impossible to tell one from another."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>considering everything</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"all in all. Examples: There were a few problems, but all in all it was a well-organized seminar. Leonard got a low grade in one subject, but all in all he's a good student."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to distribute (also: to hand out) (S); to lose consciousness</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to pass out. Comment: The verbal idiom to hand out can be made into the noun handout to refer to items that are distributed in a class or meeting. Examples: Please help me pass out these test papers; there must be a hundred of them. Alright, students, here are the class handouts for this week. The weather was so hot in the soccer stadium that some of the fans in the stands passed out.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be sufficient or adequate for everyone present; to circulate, to move from place to place</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to go around. Examples: We thought that we had bought enough food and drink for the party, but actually there wasn't enough to go around. There's a bad strain of influenza going around right now. Have you gotten your flu shots yet? Mike has been going around telling people that he was accepted to Harvard University. Do you believe him?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to block or obstruct; not to be helpful, to cause inconvenience (for both, also: to get in the/one's way)"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be in (the/one's) way. Examples: Jocelyn couldn't drive through the busy intersection because a big truck was in the way. Our small child tried to help us paint the house, but actually he just got in our way."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to gain (pounds or weight) (S); to present, to perform (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to put on. Examples: Bob has put on a lot of weight recently. He must have put at least fifteen pounds on. The Youth Actor's Guild put on a wonderful version of Romeo and Juliet at the globe Theater."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to construct, to erect (S); to lift, to raise upwards (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to put up. Examples: The construction company is tearing down that old office building in order to put up a new one. Please put your hand up if you have never studied English grammar before.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to tolerate, to accept unwillingly</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to put up with. Examples: The employee was fired because his boss could not put up with his mistakes any longer. While I'm studying, I can't put up with any noise or other distractions."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>useless, without the desired result</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"in vain. Examples: All the doctors' efforts to save the injured woman were in vain. She was declared dead three hours after being admitted to the hospital. We tried in vain to reach you last night. Is your phone out of order?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>continuously, constantly (also: day after day; for longer periods of time, year in and year out and year after year)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>day in and day out. Examples: During the month of April, it rained day in and day out. Day after day I waited for a letter from him, but one never came. Year in and year out, the weather in San Diego is the best in the nation.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to work with the purpose of fulfilling a requirement or being equal to others</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to catch up. Comment: The idiom is often followed by the preposition with and a noun phrase. It is similar in meaning to keep up with from Lesson 17. Examples: The student was absent from class so long that it took her a long time to catch up. If you are not equal to others, first you have to catch up with them before you can keep up with them.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>not to move (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to hold still. Examples: Please hold still while I adjust your tie. If you don't hold that camera still, you'll get a blurred picture."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to recognize (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to know by sight. Comment: This idiom is used when the person has been seen previously but is not known personally. The person must be used to separate the idiom. Examples: I have never met our new neighbors; I simply know them by sight. The woman said that she would know the thief by sight if she ever saw him again.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be unsatisfactory, to be improper, to be wrong</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be the matter. Comment: In a question, this idiom is used with what or something. In an answer, something or nothing is usually used. Examples: A: What is the matter, Betty? You look very upset. B: Yes, something is the matter. I've lost my purse! A: Is something the matter, Charles? You don't look well. B: No, nothing is the matter. I'm just a little under the weather."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to rear, to raise from childhood (S); to mention, to raise an issue, to introduce a topic (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to bring up. Examples: Parents should bring up their children to be responsible members of society. Sarah wanted to bring the scheduling problem up at the club meeting, but finally she decided against doing so. One of the students brought up an interesting point related to the subject in our textbook.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become lost; to go away in order not to bother</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to get lost. Comment: The second definition provides a very informal, even rude, meaning that should be used only with close friends. It is sometimes used in a joking manner. Examples: While driving in Boston, we got lost and drove many miles in the wrong direction. Todd kept bothering me while I was studying, so I told him to get lost. Lisa joked that she wanted her sister to get lost forever.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to delay, to make late (S); to remain high in quality</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to hold up. Examples: A big accident held up traffic on the highway for several hours. Deidre is amazed at how well her car has held up over the years.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to leave without permission; to escape</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to run away. Examples: The young couple ran away and got married because their parents wouldn't permit it. That cat is just like a criminal  it runs away from anyone who tries to come near!"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to refuse to consider, to prohibit (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to rule out. Examples: Heather ruled out applying to college in Texas because she would rather go to school in Canada. I'd like to watch a good movie on TV tonight, but a ton of homework rules that out."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>by a great margin, clearly</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"by far. Examples: Jacquie is by far the most intelligent student in our class. This is by far the hottest, most humid summer we've had in years."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to say good-bye upon departure by train, airplane, bus, etc. (also: to send off) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to see off. Comment: A noun or pronoun must divide the idiom. Examples: We are going to the airport to see Peter off on his trip to Europe. When I left for Cincinnati on a business trip, no one came to the train station to send me off.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to accompany a person out of a house, building, etc. (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to see out. Comment: A noun or pronoun must again divide the idiom. Examples: The Johnsons were certain to see their guests out as each one left the party. Would you please see me out to the car? It's very dark outside."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"it's no surprise that, not surprisingly"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"no wonder. Comment: This idiom derives from reducing it is no wonder that Examples: No wonder the portable heater doesn't work. It's not plugged into the electrical outlet! Jack has been out of town for several weeks. No wonder we haven't seen him recently."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to increase (also: to drive up); to be constructed, to be erected</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to go up. Comment: The second definition is the same as the one for to put up in Lesson 19, except that to go up is not used with a noun object. Examples: Economists are predicting that consumer prices are going up. Inflation always has a tendency to drive up the cost of products. A new office is going up in the downtown area. A major construction company is putting it up.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to approach (also: to come up to, to walk up to, to run up to, to drive up to, etc.)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to go up to. Comment: The related forms have the same meaning, but the type of movement is different. Examples: After the lecture, several people in the audience went up to the speaker to congratulate her. The little girl came up to me and shook my hand as if she had known me for years. Bill's friend didn't want to admit that they had gotten lost, but finally he agreed to drive up to a gas station and inquire about the correct route."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to submit or deliver something that is due (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to hand in. Examples: Every student has to hand in an original composition each week of the semester. All the salespeople hand their weekly reports in on Friday.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>in order to be prepared if</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"in case. Comment: When the idiom occurs at the end of the sentence (the second example), then the meaning is in order to be prepared if something happens. The ""something"" might be an accident, a delay, etc. Examples: You'd better close the windows in case it rains. We should be sure to leave for the airport early, just in case. Cynthia, take one of your books in case you have some time to read on our trip."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to disassemble, to separate the parts of something (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to take apart. Comment: A noun or pronoun usually divides this idiom. Examples: It is much easier to take a watch apart than it is to assemble it. The engine had a serious problem, so the mechanic had to take it apart completely in order to fix it.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to assemble (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to put together. Comment: A noun or pronoun usually divides this idiom. The preposition back is used when something has been disassembled and then is being reassembled, as in the second example. Examples: Todd followed the directions on the box but he couldn't manage to put the bicycle together properly. After the teenager took the broken video game apart and fixed it, he was unable to put it back together again."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be in a more favorable condition or situation</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be better off. Comment: The opposite of this idiom is to be worse off. Examples: Jim would be better off staying at home because of his cold. You'd be much better off working in an office than in a factory. The economies of some nations are worse off than they were several decades ago."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to have enough money to enjoy a comfortable life, to be rich (also: to be well-to-do)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to be well-off. Examples: They live in the best section of town in a large home; they are very well-off. By the time I reach the age of fifty-five, I hope to be well-to-do and to travel frequently.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to surprise, to amaze, to astonish (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take by surprise. Comment: A noun or pronoun usually divides this idiom. Examples: The offer of a high-paying position with another company took me by surprise. The president's announcement that the university was in financial trouble didn't take anyone by surprise."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to maintain contact with (also: to stay in touch with)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to keep in touch with. Comment: This idiom should be compared with to get in touch with in Lesson 9. Examples: You can telephone me every few days, and in that way we can keep in touch with each other. He promised to stay in touch with us while he was abroad. However, we were very disappointed that he never did get in touch with us.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to give the same name as another (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to name after. Examples: Helen's parents named Helen after her grandmother. My grandson is named after Calvin Coolidge, the 30th President of the United States."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to grasp tightly or firmly; to wait, to be patient</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to hold on. Comment: The second definition is often used when someone is talking on the telephone. Examples: The little girl held on to her mother's hand and refused to let go as they walked through the large crowd of people. (on the telephone) Could you please hold on a moment while I get a pencil and paper? Come on, Mike, hold on. I can't get ready so quickly."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to visit or stop somewhere briefly in order to do something</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to stop by. Examples: James had to stop by the registrar's office to submit a transcript request form. Let's stop by the supermarket and pick up a few grocery items."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to write a note to someone (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to drop (someone) a line. Examples: As soon as I get to Florida, I'll drop you a line and tell you about my new job. If you have time, drop me a line now and then while you're traveling."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to meet or find unexpectedly (also: to run across); to be perceived or judged as (also: to come off)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to come across. Examples: While Cheryl was cleaning the attic, she came across some very old coins. It took her by surprise to run across something like that. Jeff's boss comes across as a tough, unpleasant person, but actually Jeff says that he is a good employer. Some people come off quite differently than they really are."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to represent, to signify; to tolerate</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to stand for. Comment: The second definition is usually used in a negative sense. The meaning is the same as to put up with in Lesson 19. Examples: On the American flag, each star stands for one of the fifty states, and each stripe stands for one of the original thirteen colonies of the 1800s. The citizens wouldn't stand for the increase in crime in their city, so they hired more police officers and built another jail."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to have the possibility of accomplishing something</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to stand a chance. Comment: This idiom is often used with an adjective such as good or excellent. It also occurs in the negative, sometimes with the adjective much. Examples: The New York baseball team stands a good chance of winning the World Series this year. Because John doesn't have any previous work experience, he doesn't stand a chance of getting that job. The woman injured in the serious train accident doesn't stand much chance of surviving."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to work carefully and conscientiously</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take pains. Examples: She takes pains to do everything well; she's our best employee. He took great pains with his last assignment because he needed to get an excellent grade to pass the class."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to watch as a spectator, to observe</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to look on. Examples: Hundreds of people were looking on as the police and firefighters rescued the passengers in the wrecked train. I stayed with my son at his first soccer practice and looked on as the coach worked with the boys.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to admire, to respect greatly</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to look up to. Examples: Children will most certainly look up to their parents if the children are brought up well. Everyone looks up to the director of our department because he is a kind and generous person.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to feel superior to, to think of someone as less important</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to look down on. Examples: People who are in positions of power should be careful not to look down on those who work for them. Why does Alma look down on Mario; just because his family is so poor?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to leave the ground (for airplanes); to leave, often in a hurry</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to take off. Comment: The noun form takeoff derives from this idiom. Examples: The plane took off over an hour late. The passengers had to buckle their seatbelts during takeoff. Do you have to take off already? You just arrived an hour ago!
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to succeed in doing something difficult (S); to exit to the side of a highway</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to pull off. Examples: The group of investors pulled off a big deal by buying half the stock in that company. I wonder how they pulled it off before the company could prevent it. The motorist pulled off when the police officer turned on the red lights and the siren.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to operate accurately (for watches and clocks)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to keep time. Comment: This idiom is usually used with adjectives such as good and perfect. Examples: Although this is a cheap watch, it keeps good time. The old clock keeps perfect time; it's never fast or slow."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to manage, to cope</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to make do with. Comment: This idiom is used when a person must accept a substitute that is not the most suitable. Examples: Pearl doesn't have a clean blouse so she has to make do with the one she wore yesterday. During difficult economic times, many people have to make do with less."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to bear a human being or animal</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to give birth to. Examples: Jane's mother has just given birth to twin girls. The zoo's Siberian tiger just gave birth to a baby cub."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>a situation involving a narrow escape from danger (also: close shave)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>close call. Examples: Bob, that car nearly hit us! What a close call. We had a close call when a small fire in our kitchen almost spread to the rest of the house.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to annoy or disturb (also: to bug)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get on one's nerves. Examples: Laura loves to talk to anyone. Sometimes her chatter really gets on my nerves. Jack asked his neighbor to turn down the stereo because it was bugging him and he couldn't concentrate."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to suppress, to quell (S); to criticize unfairly (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to put down. Examples: The police arrived just in time to put down the disturbance before it got very serious. Fred tries his best at playing tennis. You shouldn't put him down like that."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be sold at a certain price; to seek or strive for</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to go for. Examples: This dress probably goes for about $50, don't you think? Peter was going for first place in the swim meet, but he wasn't able to do better than third place."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to have as an interest, such as a sport or hobby (also: to go for, to be into, to get into)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to go in for. Examples: Hal goes in for tennis while his wife goes in for painting and sculpture. What sports are you into? I don't have any time to get into sports."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to remain awake, not to go to bed</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to stay up. Examples: I want to stay up tonight and watch a late movie on TV. He stays up every night until after one o'clock, preparing his homework."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to remain at home, not to go out</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to stay in. Comment: An idiom with the opposite meaning is to stay out. Examples: On a rainy day, I like to stay in and read. Young people are able to stay out late at night and get very little sleep.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to assume control or responsibility for (S); to do or perform again (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take over. Comment: The meaning of the second definition is almost the same as do over in Lesson 11. Also for the second definition, a noun or pronoun must divide the idiom. Examples: That large investment company specializes in taking over smaller businesses that are in financial trouble. Most students didn't do well on the important test, so the instructor let them take it over. Little Mikey didn't have much chance to hit the baseball during practice, so the coach let him take his turn over."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to appear, to arrive; to be found or located (also for the second definition: to turn up)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to show up. Examples: It really gets on my nerves that Ursula shows up late for every meeting. Willie hopes that the watch he lost last Sunday shows up soon. We've looked everywhere for that book, but it hasn't turned up yet."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to empty, to tidy by removing (S); to steal, to rob (S); to buy or purchase all of something (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to clean out. Examples: It's time for you to clean out your closet so that you can store more things in there. A burglar entered my apartment while I was gone and cleaned me out. He took over $200 in cash and jewelry. Thousands of shoppers cleaned out the store that had gone bankrupt and was selling all its remaining products at very reduced prices."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to make unconscious (S); to impress or attract greatly (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to knock out. Comment: This idiom can be made into the noun form knockout for both definitions. Examples: The prizefighter knocked out his opponent with one punch in the first five seconds of the first round. It was the fastest knockout in boxing history. Linda's beautiful appearance and slender figure really knock me out. Isn't she a real knockout tonight?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to work very hard (sometimes too hard) to do something</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to knock oneself out. Comment: A reflexive pronoun must divide the idiom. Examples: She really knocked herself out trying to pass that difficult class. Don't knock yourself out during practice. Save your strength for the competition later."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to accomplish, to execute (S) (also: to go through with)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to carry out. Examples: It's easy to write down a plan for losing weight, but much harder to carry it out. Charles promised to go through with his plan to enroll in graduate school and get an advanced degree."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to meet someone unexpectedly; to crash or collide into (also: to bump into)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to run into. Examples: It was a shock to run into an old friend from high school recently. The drunk driver was slightly injured when he ran into a telephone pole.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to start traveling toward a place (also: to set off, to head out); to arrange or display neatly (also: to lay out) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to set out. Examples: We set out for the top of the mountain at dawn. Unfortunately, as we set off, it started to snow heavily, so we decided to head out again later. The children tried to set out the dishes on the table, but their dad had to help to lay the dishes out properly.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to intend to, to act purposefully to</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to set out to do something. Examples: We set out to paint the house in one day but quickly realized that it would be impossible to do so. Janet set out to compete for the large scholarship grant by writing a good essay.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to create by drawing, such as a map (S); to prepare documents or legal papers (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to draw up. Examples: Max asked me to draw up a map to the party so that he wouldn't get lost. Our lawyer agreed to draw the contract up as soon as possible."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>compromise, cooperation between people</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>give and take. Examples: Give and take is an important element of a successful marriage. Most business negotiations involve give and take between the parties involved.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to stop attending; to withdraw from</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to drop out of. Comment: This idiom can be made into the noun form dropout. Examples: Some students drop out of secondary school early in order to get jobs. However, such dropouts often regret their decision later in life. Two more baseball teams have dropped out of the youth league due to a lack of players.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to accept as true, have faith in</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to believe in. Examples: Some people believe in being honest in all human affairs, while others accept the need to lie in order to get one's way. Throughout the history of man, some cultures have believed in one god while others have believed in the existence of many gods."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to make happier, to feel less sad (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to cheer up. Examples: We all tried to cheer up the little boy when he started to cry. After the death of Deanne's husband, it was difficult to cheer her up at all."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be sensible or reasonable</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to make sense. Examples: It makes sense to wait until a sunny day to visit the park together. That Jimmy ran away from home suddenly doesn't make sense to any of us."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to depart quickly (also: to storm out); to act suddenly</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to burst out. Comment: For the second definition, this idiom is usually followed by a gerund form such as laughing, crying, singing, etc. Examples: Faye and Debbie were so angry at each other that one of them burst out the front door of the house and the other stormed out the back door. It was so funny to see a little baby in the audience burst out crying when the choir group burst out singing at the start of the recital.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to get free, to escape</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to get away. Examples: We always try to get away from the noise and heat of the city for a month or two each summer. No one knows how the suspected criminal got away from the police.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to avoid punishment for</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get away with. Examples: Jonathan tries to get away with coming late to work almost every day; someday he'll suffer the consequences. Terence can't continue to put his friends down like that and expect to get away with it forever."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to receive one's just punishment (S)"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to serve (someone) right. Comment: This idiom is usually used at the beginning of a sentence after the subject it. Compare the following examples with those in the previous idiom above. Examples: It serves Jonathan right to be fired from his job. It serves Terence right that none of his friends are willing to help him move to a new apartment.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to prevent from sleeping (S); to continue maintaining (speed, level of work, condition, etc.) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to keep up. Examples: Could you please turn down the TV volume? You're keeping up the children. If we can keep up this speed, we should arrive there in about two hours. James is so proud of his daughter for getting mostly A's in school. He's certain that she can keep up the good work. The Federal Reserve Bank hopes to keep the value of the dollar up at least through the rest of the year."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to have current knowledge of; to understand as an explanation</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to keep up with. Comment: This idiom should be compared to the meaning of to keep up with in Lesson 17. Examples: Evan keeps up with world affairs by reading a news magazine each week. I understand a lot of the Spanish language, but I can't keep up with the fast conversation in this Mexican film."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be easily visible or noticeable (also: to stick out)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to stand out. Comment: This idiom is used for someone or something that is different from all others. Examples: Her bright red hair makes her stand out from others in the group. Brandon Styles is a tall, distinguished gentleman who sticks out in any crowd.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to reveal or tell what you know, to hint</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to let on. Examples: We are going to the movies tonight and we don't want Doris to go. If you see her, make sure not to let on. They asked me not to let on to Ted that we're planning the birthday party; it's supposed to be a big surprise."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to fail, to result badly</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to go wrong. Examples: Something went wrong with the engine, so we had to have the car towed to a garage. Shawn should have been here over an hour ago; I'm certain that something went wrong."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to compromise with someone</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to meet (someone) halfway. Examples: Steve wanted $4,500 for his car, and Gwen offered $4,000. They met each other halfway and agreed on $4,250. After a long process of give and take, the owners of the company agreed to meet the workers halfway by providing some additional health benefits but no wage increase.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to examine with the purpose of determining condition (also: to check on)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to check up on. Comment: This idiom has the related noun form checkup. Examples: The government always checks up on the background of employees who are hired for sensitive military projects. The doctor wants me to have a thorough medical checkup as part of a preventive medicine program.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to point or place upwards (S); to rob (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to stick up. Examples: You should put some water on your hair. It's sticking up in the back. A masked thief stuck up a grocery store in the neighborhood last night."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to happen</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to come about. Examples: I didn't find any explanation in the newspaper about how the political coup came about. The flood came about as a result of the heavy winter rains."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to cause to happen</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to bring about. Comment: This idiom is used to indicate who or what caused something to come about. Examples: John brought about the accident because of his carelessness. The heavy rains we have each spring bring about serious flooding.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to increase slowly, to make stronger gradually (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to build up. Examples: They built up their savings account so that they could buy a new house. The professional athlete exercises regularly to build her strength up.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to decrease, to lessen in strength</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to die down. Examples: The hurricane became a less serious tropical storm when its winds died down. We let the fire in the fireplace die down and enjoyed watching the embers as they glowed in the dark.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to diminish gradually in time or distance</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to fade away. Examples: The memory of that unpleasant experience has slowly faded away. The music of the band gradually faded away as the parade passed down the street.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>not to exist anymore; to be in the process of disappearing</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to die out. Examples: Scientists still are not sure exactly why the dinosaurs died out. That strange, new style of dancing is slowly dying out.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to read or see clearly (S); to prepare a legal document, such as a will, a check, etc. (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to make out. Examples: The letter was so poorly handwritten that I couldn't make out many of the words. Harold, please make the check out to Acme Piano Company."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to fulfill (a standard or promise)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to live up to. Examples: It was clear that the lazy student would never live up to his family's expectations. It surprised us that the car salesperson lived up to all the promises he made."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to adhere to (a promise), to follow or obey (a set of rules, procedures, etc.)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to stick to. Examples: He made a promise to his wife to quit smoking and drinking, and so far he has stuck to it. All organizations expect their employees to stick to established work rules and procedures. If you try hard to stick to your principles, then you'll be able to live up to them."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to cheat, to take unfair advantage of (also: to rip off, the ripoff)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to stick it to somebody. Examples: Be careful in doing business with that salesperson. He'll stick it to you at the first opportunity. The car dealership certainly ripped me off when I bought this car. It has caused me trouble constantly. You paid over $400 for that jacket? What a ripoff!"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to insist on, to demand; to defend, to support</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to stand up for. Examples: If you don't stand up for your rights in court, the lawyers will try to stick it to you. Frank stood up for his friend, who was being put down by other teenagers nearby."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to economize, to save money</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to cut corners. Examples: Most students live on limited budgets and have to cut corners whenever possible. The Livingstons have nine children, so it is essential that they cut corners at all times.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to employ, to hire (S); to accept responsibility for, to undertake</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to take on. Examples: That factory is taking a lot of new employees on for its new production line. Would you be willing to take on the task of organizing the next company picnic?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to remove from an elevated place (S); to write what is said, to note</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to take down. Examples: We should take the pictures down from the wall and clean off the dust. The secretary took down everything that was said at the meeting.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to fail to materialize, not to succeed</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to fall through. Comment: This idiom is usually used with the noun plan or plans as the subject. Examples: Our plan to travel to Europe last summer fell through when we were unable to save up enough money. Felix made plans to have a party for everyone in his office, but they fell through at the last moment.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to lag, to fail to keep up (also: to get behind)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to fall behind. Examples: Eve fell behind in her studies and finally had to drop out of school. If you get behind in your car payments, the finance company may repossess it from you.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to surrender, to stop resisting</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to give in. Examples: Completely surrounded by our soldiers, the enemy finally gave in. Management gave in to the strikers' demands and agreed to a shortened work week."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to release, to produce</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to give off. Examples: When water boils, it gives off steam. The flowers in this garden give off a strange odor.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to distribute; to become exhausted or depleted (also: to run out)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to give out. Comment: The first definition has the same meaning as the second definition of to pass out in Lesson 19. Examples: An usher stood at the door of the theater giving out programs. I couldn't finish the ten-mile race because my energy gave out. Jeff plans to stay in Las Vegas and gamble until his money runs out."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to want revenge on, to feel hostile towards (also: to hold a grudge against)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to have it in for. Examples: Martina expects to lose her job because her boss has had it in for her for a long time. The teacher has held a grudge against Al ever since the time that he insulted her in front of the class.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to quarrel with, to confront</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to have it out with. Examples: I am going to have it out with Jack about all the times that he has told us lies. Ben had it out with his roommate about coming back home so late and making a lot of noise.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to delay, or to be delayed, in occurring (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to hold off. Comment: This idiom has the same meaning as to put off in Lesson 5 when a noun or pronoun is used as an object, as in the second example. Examples: If the rain holds off for a few more days, they can finish planting the rest of the crop. The judge agreed to hold off making a decision until new evidence could be introduced into court.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to endure, to be sufficient; to survive by resisting; to persist in one's efforts"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to hold out. Comment: The first definition for to hold out has the opposite meaning of the second definition for to give out (seventh idiom, this lesson). Examples: If our supply of food and water holds out, we plan to camp here for another week. However, whenever it gives out, we'll have to leave. That nation's troops cannot hold out much longer against the superior forces of the enemy. The valuable football player held out for more money before signing a new contract with his team."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to extend, to keep for a longer time (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to hold over. Examples: They are going to hold over that movie for another week because so many people are coming to see it. Let's hold discussion of this problem over until our next meeting."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to slacken, to lessen in intensity; to relax or ease one's effort (also: related idiom: to take it easy)"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to let up. Examples: If the rain doesn't let up soon, we won't be able to have our picnic. When Jane is working, she never lets up for a moment. Jane should take it easy or she'll get exhausted."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to abstain from, stop using as a habit; to release or discharge from a job (also: related idiom: to let go) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to lay off. Examples: If you're trying to lose weight, you should lay off sweet things. If business continues to be slow, we will have to lay off some workers. It will be necessary to let the youngest employees go first."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to show or introduce (to the public) (S); to make available (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to bring out. Examples: Most automobile companies bring out new models each year. My mother brought some snacks out for my friends and me to have.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to return a bought or borrowed item (also: to take back) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to bring back. Comment: To bring back is used when you are speaking at the place that an item is bought or borrowed; To take back is used when speaking at another place. Examples: Ma'am, our store policy is that you can bring back the dress as long as you have your sales receipt. You can borrow my car if you promise to bring it back by six o'clock. I have to take this book back to the library today."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to wait until late at night without going to bed</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to wait up for. Examples: Don't wait up for me. I may be back after midnight. We waited up for our son until two o'clock in the morning before we called the police."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>not to disturb, to stay away from (S) (also: to let alone)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to leave (someone or something) alone. Examples: Leave the baby alone for a while and she may go to sleep. After the cat had scratched Peter twice, he let it alone.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>and certainly not (also: not to mention, to say nothing of)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"let alone. Comment: Let alone is used after negative forms. The example that follows let alone is much less possible than the example that precedes let alone. Examples: I'm too sick today to walk to the kitchen, let alone go to the zoo with you. He doesn't even speak his own language well, let alone French."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to terminate, to discontinue (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to break off. Examples: After war began, the two countries broke off diplomatic relations. Elsa and Bob were once engaged, but they have already broken it off.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to disappear gradually</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to wear off. Examples: My headache isn't serious. It will wear off after an hour or so. The effect of the painkilling drug didn't wear off for several hours."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become worn gradually through use (also: to wear away, to wear through) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to wear down. Comment: Compare with to wear out (to become useless from wear) in Lesson 8. Examples: If you drag your feet while you walk, you'll wear down your shoes quickly. The pounding of ocean waves against the coast gradually wears it away. Johnny has worn through the seat of his pants. Helga threw away that dress because she had worn it out."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>in general, in most ways (also: by and large)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>on the whole. Examples: He is, on the whole, a good student. By and large, I agree with your suggestions.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>risky, uncertain until the end</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>touch and go. Examples: The complicated medical operation was touch and go for several hours. The outcome of the soccer final was touch and go for the entire match.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to exercise; to develop, to devise (a plan) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to work out. Examples: Jane works out at the fitness center every other morning before going to school. The advertising department worked out a plan to increase company sales. We couldn't come up with a good plan for solving the problem, but we agreed to work it out at a later date."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to drive or go backwards (S); to defend, to support (S); to return to a previous thought</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to back up. Examples: I couldn't back my car up because there was a bicycle in the driveway behind me. Ursula asked her friends to go back her up when she went to court to fight a ticket for an illegal lane change on the highway. Wait a minute. Could you back up and say that again?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to drive a vehicle out of a parking space (S); to withdraw support, to fail to fulfill a promise or obligation</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to back out. Examples: The parking lot attendant had to back another car out before he could get to mine. We were all ready to sign the contracts when one of the parties to the agreement backed out.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to desire greatly, to be determined to</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to have one's heart set on. Examples: She has her heart set on taking a trip abroad. She's been thinking about it for months. Todd has his heart set on going to medical school and becoming a doctor."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to buy the complete stock of (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to buy up. Examples: Before the hurricane struck, residents bought up all the food and water in local stores. The government plans to buy up all surplus grain in order to stabilize the price.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to purchase a business or company (S); to purchase all of a person's shares or stock (S)"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to buy out. Comment: This idiom is similar in meaning to take over in Lesson 23. Examples: Larger companies often buy out smaller companies that are having financial difficulties. Mr. Lee has been trying for some time to buy his partner out so that he can control the company by himself.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to sell all items (S); to arrange for the sale of a company or business (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to sell out. Examples: That store is closing its doors for good and is selling out everything this weekend. If my new business enterprise is successful, I'll sell it out for a few million dollars."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become popular or widespread; to understand, to appreciate a joke</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to catch on. Comment: This idiom is often used with the preposition to for the second definition. Examples: Fashions of the past often catch on again among young people. When the teacher speaks quickly like that, can you catch on easily? His joke was very funny at the time, but when I told it to others later, nobody seemed to catch on. I had to tell the joke again before anyone could catch on to it.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to have the necessary skills or talent for</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to be cut out for. Comment: The idiom is most often used in the negative or in questions. Examples: John is certainly not cut out for the work of a trial lawyer. Are you certain that you are cut out for that kind of job?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to discard (S); to remove by force (S); to refuse to consider, to reject (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to throw out. Examples: Instead of throwing out our paper waste in the office, we should recycle it. When a fight broke out between two people on the dance floor, the management threw them out. The judge threw the case out because there was insufficient evidence to try the defendant successfully.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to erect or construct quickly (S); to vomit (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to throw up. Examples: The Red Cross threw up temporary shelters for the homeless victims of the earthquake. The ill patient is unable to digest her food properly, so she is throwing all of it up.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to make understandable (also: to straighten out) (S); to become sunny</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to clear up. Examples: The teacher tried to clear up our confusion about the meaning of the difficult paragraph in the reading. It's rather cloudy this morning. Do you think that it will clear up later?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to go, or cause to go, more slowly (also: to slow up) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to slow down. Comment: This idiom can be used both with and without an object. Examples: The car was going so fast that the motorist couldn't slow it down enough to make the sharp curve. You're eating too fast to digest your food well. Slow down! Slow up a bit! You're talking so quickly that I can't catch on well."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to lose, or cause to lose, all moisture (S); to be depleted</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to dry up. Examples: Every summer the extreme heat in this valley dries the stream up. All funds for the project dried up when the local government faced a budget crisis.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to lose, or cause to lose, moisture gradually (S); to stop drinking alcohol in excess (also: to sober up)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to dry out. Examples: Martha hung the towel outside on the clothesline in order to dry it out. Some people go to alcohol recovery centers in order to dry out.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be doing something; to be planning or plotting something, scheming</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be up to (something). Comment: The first definition usually takes the form of a question. Examples: Hi, Jake. I haven't seen you in a long time. What have you been up to? Those boys hiding behind the building must be up to something bad."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to avoid discussing directly, to evade the issue</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to beat around the bush. Examples: Our boss beats around the bush so much that no one in the office knows exactly what he wants us to do. Instead of beating around the bush, Melinda explained her objection in very clear terms.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to end, to stop</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to come to an end. Comment: This idiom is used with finally and never when some activity lasts too long. Examples: The meeting finally came to an end at ten o'clock in the evening. Even though my friend seemed to enjoy the movie, I thought that it would never come to an end."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to cause to end, to terminate in a definite manner (also: to do away with)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to put an end to. Examples: The dictatorial government put an end to organized opposition in the country by making it illegal to form a political party. It may never be possible to do away with all forms of prejudice and discrimination in the world.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to seek revenge, to retaliate</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get even with. Comment: This idiom is similar in meaning to to have it in for in Lesson 27. Examples: Bill has had it in for his boss for a long time. He told me he's planning to get even with his boss by giving some company secrets to a competitor. I want to get even with Steve for beating me so badly in tennis last time. The scores were 6-1 and 6-2."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to waste time (also: to screw around); to joke, not to be serious</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to fool around. Examples: The teacher got angry because her students were fooling around and couldn't finish their work before the end of class. Sometimes I wish that Pat would stop fooling around so much and talk about something more interesting to others."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to face, to overlook</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to look out on. Examples: We really enjoy our new apartment that looks out on a river. Their rear window looks out on a lovely garden.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to cause anger (S); to create (trouble or difficulty) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to stir up. Examples: The senseless murder of a small child stirred up the whole neighborhood. The boss is in a bad mood today so don't stir her up with any more customer complaints."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to visit in order to enjoy (S); to decrease the size of clothes (S); to deceive, to fool (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to take in. Examples: We decided to take in Toronto on our trip to Canada, and that is where we took in the most memorable outdoor stage play we have ever seen. Lois lost so much weight that she had her skirts and slacks taken in by her tailor. The fraudulent investment advisor took everyone in with his sincere manner and generous promises. Most investors lost all their money.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to undergo, to experience; to consume, to use (also: to use up)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to go through. Comment: The first definition is used when someone is having some hardship or difficulty. Examples: I can't believe what she went through to get that job. She had four interviews with the hiring committee in one week! Frank said that they had gone through all the toilet paper in the house, but Steve couldn't believe that they had used it all up."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be known without the need to mention</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to go without saying. Comment: This idiom occurs with a that-clause, often with the pronoun it as the subject. Examples: It goes without saying that you shouldn't drive quickly in bad weather. That he will gain weight if he continues to eat and drink so much goes without saying."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to mislead by joking or tricking (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to put (someone) on. Comment: This idiom is usually used in a continuous tense form. A noun object must divide the idiom. Examples: Don't worry. I wouldn't expect you do all that work by yourself. I'm just putting you on. Jack can't be serious about what he said. He must be putting us on."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to remain calm during an emergency</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to keep one's head. Examples: When the heater caused a fire, Gloria kept her head and phoned for assistance right away; otherwise, the whole house might have burned down. When the boat starting sinking in heavy seas, the crew members kept their heads and led the passengers to the lifeboats."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"not to think clearly, to lose one's self-control"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to lose one's head. Examples: When Mel saw a dog in the street right in front of his car, he lost his head and drove onto the sidewalk and into a tree. If the politician hadn't gotten stirred up and lost his head, he never would have criticized his opponent unfairly."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>not willing to accept the ideas of others (the opposite of narrow minded is broad-minded)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>narrow-minded. Examples: Narrow-minded people tend to discriminate against groups of people with which they have nothing in common. Ted is so broad-minded that he has almost no standards by which he judges others.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to withstand use or wear; to fail to appear for a date or social engagement (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to stand up. Examples: My old car has stood up well over the years. I haven't had any major problems at all. Janet was very angry because her new boyfriend stood her up on their second date. She waited over an hour for him before returning home."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to win or defeat by gaining an advantage over someone</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get the better of. Examples: Jim doesn't seem very athletic at tennis, but if you're not careful, he'll get the better of you. Lynn gets frustrated when Bruce gets the better of her in arguments. No matter what she says, he always has a clever response."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become free or loose, to escape</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to break loose. Examples: During the bad storm, the boat broke loose from the landing and drifted out to sea. One bicyclist broke loose from the pack of racers and pulled ahead towards the finish line.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>nervous, anxious; upset, irritable</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"on edge. Examples: Cynthia was on edge all day about the important presentation she had to give to the local citizens group. I don't like being around Jake when he's on edge like that. Someone should tell him to calm down and relax."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>not be able to convince someone</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to waste one's breath. Comment: This idiom is used when someone is wasting time trying to convince another person. The idiom to save one's breath is related and means not to waste effort trying to convince someone. Examples: Don't argue with Frank any longer. You are wasting your breath trying to get him to agree with you. I have already decided what I'm going to do. You can't change my mind, so save your breath."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to make shorter, to interrupt (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to cut short. Examples: The moderator asked the speaker to cut short his talk because there wasn't much time remaining for questions from the audience. We were very unfortunate when we received bad news from home that forced us to cut our trip short."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become involved or concerned with something; to enter a place for a brief time (also: to step into)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to step in. Examples: When the children started fighting on the play-ground, a teacher had to step in and stop the fight. The supervisor asked one of the employees to step in her office for a moment. Would you step into the hallway so that I can show you the information posted on the bulletin board?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to retire or leave a top position, to resign</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to step down. Examples: Next May the principal will step down after thirty-five years of service to the school. The angry shareholders wanted the company president to step down because of the stock scandal.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to treat severely, to discipline; to go faster, to work more quickly</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to step on. Comment: For the second definition, the idiom is followed by the pronoun it. Examples: Sometimes it's necessary to step on children when they do something dangerous. We're going to be late for the movies. You'd better step on it!"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>very inexpensive, a bargain</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"a steal. Comment: This idiom is often used in an exclamation using what. Examples: I can't believe that I paid only $2,000 for this three-year-old car. What a steal! Scott considered it a steal when he bought a complete bedroom set for only $99."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to behave so as to gain favor with someone</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to play up to. Examples: The other students in the class resent Jim because he plays up to the teacher in order to get better grades. When my children asked me to go shopping for a new video game, I knew why they had been playing up to me all morning.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>approximately, almost; somewhat, to a certain degree</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"more or less. Examples: Although your bedroom feels smaller, it's more or less the same size as mine. Ted more or less agreed with our decision to put off the meeting until more members could show up. At least he didn't object strongly."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to confuse, to scramble (S); to cause problems in (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to screw up. Examples: Chris had trouble finding Jane's apartment because the addresses of the buildings screwed him up. Instead of fixing the television set, the technician screwed it up even more."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to perform badly, to make a mistake (also: to mess up, to slip up)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to goof up. Examples: I really goofed up on the exam today; did you mess up, too? Karen slipped up when she forgot to deposit money into her checking account.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to get very angry and do something hastily</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to go off the deep end. Examples: Just because you had a serious argument with your supervisor, you didn't have to go off the deep end and resign, did you? When Dan's wife demanded a divorce, he went off the deep end again. This time he was shouting so that the whole neighborhood could hear."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to fail at what one used to do well</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to lose one's touch. Examples: Milton used to be the best salesman at the car dealership, but recently he seems to have lost his touch. I used to play tennis very well, but today you beat me easily. I must be losing my touch."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>under firm control, well managed</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"in hand. Examples: The copilot asked the pilot if he had the plane in hand or whether he needed any help navigating through the severe thunderstorm. The police officer radioed to the station that she had the emergency situation in hand and didn't require any assistance."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>available, nearby</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>on hand. Comment: This idiom is often followed by in case. Examples: I always keep some extra money on hand in case I forget to get cash from the bank. The concert organizers arranged to have some security guards on hand in case there were any problems during the performance.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to discuss informally (over a period of time) (S) (also: to toss around)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to kick (something) around. Examples: At first my friends were reluctant to consider my suggestion, but they finally were willing to kick it around for a while. Herb thought that we should kick around the idea of establishing a special fund for supporting needy members of the club.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>be attentive, competent, alert</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"be on the ball. Examples: Jim was the only one who caught that serious error in the bookkeeping statements. He's really on the ball. Ella was certainly on the ball when she remembered to reconfirm our flight arrangements. All the rest of us would have forgotten."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to meet or fulfill a missed obligation at a later time (S); to create, to invent (an idea) (S); to apply cosmetics to (S); to comprise, to be composed of</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to make up. Comment: Note that all of the definitions are separable except the last one. Examples: The teacher allowed several students who missed the exam to make it up during the next class. The little boy made up a bad excuse for wearing his dirty shoes in the house, so his mother punished him. Dee was able to make her face up in half the normal time because she didn't use much makeup. Two separate bodies  the House of Representatives and the Senate  make up the Congress of the United States."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to resolve differences with</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to make up with. Comment: This idiom is used for differences of opinion between friends and lovers. Examples: Gundula made up with her roommate after their serious misunderstanding about arrangements for the party. After the bad quarrel the two lovers kissed and made up with each other.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to gather, to collect (information) (S); to gain control of one's emotions (S)"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to pull together. Comment: A reflexive pronoun must be used for the second definition. Examples: The reporter pulled together information from several sources in preparing the newspaper article. Mr. Simpson was so frightened when he heard footsteps behind him on the lonely, dark street that it took several minutes to pull himself together.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to appear promising or optimistic, to be improving</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to be looking up. Comment: This idiom is used in a continuous tense, very often with the subject things. Examples: The board chairman is glad to report that things are looking up for the company after several years of declining sales. Prospects for building that new library in the downtown area are looking up.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to stop a bad habit</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to kick the habit. Examples: Once a child becomes accustomed to chewing his nails, it's difficult to kick the habit. The doctor advised the heavy cigarette smoker that her heart had become damaged and that she should kick the habit right away."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to conceal, to hide (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to cover up. Comment: This idiom is used for events which are potentially embarrassing to one's reputation, as well as against the law. The noun coverup can be formed. Examples: The office worker tried to cover up his crimes, but everyone knew that he had been stealing office supplies all along. The political coverup of the bribery scandal failed and was reported by all the major media."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to fall asleep; to take to a certain location (S); to decrease (for the third definition, also: to fall off)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to drop off. Examples: My mother dropped off during the boring television show; her head was nodding up and down. I don't mind dropping you off at the store on my way to work. Business has been dropping off rapidly recently, but fortunately it hasn't been falling off as quickly as for our competitors."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to place upside down (S); to flip, to turn upside down; to pass or give control to someone (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to turn over. Examples: The teacher asked the students to turn the answer sheet over and to write a short essay on the back. The car was going too fast around the corner and turned over twice. Mr. Collins has decided to turn over his jewelry store to his son at the end of the year.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to send a request through the normal way</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to go through channels. Comment: This idiom can be used with the adjective proper. Examples: If you go through proper channels in this company, it's sometimes impossible to get anything done quickly. The police told the important civic leader that even she had to go through channels in reporting the burglary of her house."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>the final event in a series of unacceptable actions</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"the last straw. Comment: This idiom is always used with the definite article the. Examples: When John asked to borrow money from me for the fourth time, it was the last straw. I finally told him that I couldn't lend him any more. I can't believe that my roommate left the door to our apartment unlocked again. It's the last straw; I'm moving out."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become unable or afraid to do something</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to get cold feet. Comment: This idiom is usually used in the case of an important or dangerous action. Examples: Karl was supposed to marry Elaine this weekend, but at the last moment he got cold feet. Only one of the rock climbers got cold feet when the group reached the base of the hundred-meter cliff.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to receive credit for the value of an old item towards the purchase of a new item (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to trade in. Comment: This idiom is used to form the noun trade-in. Examples: The car dealership offered me $1,000 for my old car if I traded it in for a new model. The appliance company was offering a $50 trade-in during the special promotion for its new line of refrigerators.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>direct, personal; directly, personally (written without hyphens)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"face-to-face. Comment: This idiom can be used both as an adjective (the first definition) and as an adverb (the second definition). Examples: The workers' representatives had a face-to-face meeting with the management to resolve the salary issue. The stepmother and her teenage son talked face to face about his troubles in school."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to support, to back (also: to go along with); to understand or follow what someone is saying</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be with (someone). Examples: Although others thought that we shouldn't go along with Jerry, I told Jerry that I was with him on his proposal for reorganizing the staff. After turning left at the traffic light, go two blocks and turn right on Madison. After three more blocks, turn right again. Are you still with me?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be able to focus or concentrate on (also: to get with it)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be with it. Comment: To be with it in the negative has the same meaning as to feel out of it. The related form to get with it is used in commands. Examples: Jack's really with it today. I've never seen him play such good soccer. You've done only a small amount of work in two hours. You're not with it today, are you? It's no excuse to say that you feel out of it. We need everyone's help on this, so get with it!"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to fall in love quickly; to be fooled or tricked by</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to fall for. Examples: Samantha and Derek never expected to fall for each other like they did, but they got married within two weeks of having met. The Masons wanted to believe their son, but unfortunately they had fallen for his lies too many times to be deceived once again.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>it seems likely, reasonable, or typical</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>it figures. Comment: This idiom is either followed by a that-clause or by no other part of grammar. Examples: It figures that the children were willing to help with the yardwork only if they received a reward for doing so. When I told Evan that his secretary was unhappy about not getting a raise, he said that it figured.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to inform, to give background information to (also: to clue in) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to fill (someone) in. Comment: This idiom is often followed by the preposition on and a noun phrase containing the pertinent information. Examples: Could you fill me in on what is going to be discussed at tomorrow's meeting? Not having been to the convention, my associate asked me to clue him in on the proceedings."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to motivate to behave or act in a certain way (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to make (someone) tick. Comment: This idiom is used within a what-clause. Examples: If a salesperson knows what makes a customer tick, he will be able to sell a lot of merchandise. It's been impossible for us to figure out what makes our new boss tick. One moment she seems pleasant and then the next moment she's upset."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to take someone's place temporarily, to substitute for; to protect someone by lying or deceiving"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to cover for. Examples: Go ahead and take your coffee break. I'll cover for you until you return. The criminal made his wife cover for him when the police asked if the man had been home all day. She swore that he had been there."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to provide a person with another opportunity or chance (S); not to expect too much work from (S); not to expect someone to believe (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to give (someone) a break. Comment: Command forms are most common with this idiom. For the third definition, the pronoun me must be used. Examples: The driver pleaded with the police officer to give him a break and not issue him a ticket for speeding. When the students heard how much homework the teacher wanted them to do over the holiday, they begged, ""Give us a break, Professor Doyle!"" Oh, Jim, give me a break! That's a terrible excuse for being late."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to stop doing as a regular activity, to remove oneself from a situation</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to bow out. Comment: The related idiom to want out indicates that someone desires to bow out. Examples: She bowed out as the school's registrar after sixteen years of service. One of the two partners wanted out of the deal because they couldn't agree on the terms of the contract."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to find guilty of a crime or offense (S) (also: to hang on)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to pin on. Comment: This idiom is divided by a noun phrase containing the crime or offense. The accused person is mentioned after the preposition on. Examples: The prosecuting attorney tried to pin the murder on the victim's husband, but the jury returned a verdict of ""not guilty."" I wasn't anywhere near the window when it got broken. You can't pin that on me."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to provoke a response from</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get a rise out of. Comment: This idiom is usually used when someone is teased into responding in anger or annoyance. Examples: You can kid me all day about my mistake, but you won't get a rise out of me. I got a rise out of Marvin when I teased him about his weight. Marvin weighs over two-hundred pounds."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to stay or remain where one is, to wait</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to stick around. Comment: This idiom is used when someone is waiting for something to happen or for someone to arrive. Examples: Todd had to stick around the house all day until the new furniture was finally delivered in the late afternoon. Why don't you stick around for a while and see if Sarah eventually shows up?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to pay the cost or bill</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to pick up the tab. Comment: This idiom applies when someone pays for the cost of another person's meal, tickets, etc. Examples: The advertising manager is flying to Puerto Rico for a conference, and her firm is picking up the tab. The government picked up the tab for the visiting dignitary. It paid for all of the lodging and meals, as well as transportation, during his stay."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>incidentally</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"by the way. Comment: This idiom is used when someone thinks of something further in the course of a conversation. Examples: Movies are my favorite form of entertainment. Oh, by the way, have you seen the new picture that's playing at the Bijou? Vera's been divorced for three years now. She told me, by the way, that she never plans to remarry."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to do something with enthusiasm and thoroughness</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to go to town. Examples: Our interior decorator really went to town in remodeling our living room. I'm afraid to ask how much it's going to cost. Charlie really went to town on his research project. He consulted over forty reference works and wrote a ninety-page report."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to neglect a duty (S); to ignore a situation (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to let slide. Examples: Terry knew that she should have paid the electric bill on time instead of letting it slide. Now the utility company has turned off her service. When he tried to get a rise out of me by mentioning my failure to receive a promotion at work, I just let it slide.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"I don't know (also: beats me)"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"search me. Comment: This idiom is used informally, usually as a command form. Examples: When Elmer asked his wife if she knew why the new neighbors left their garage door open all night, she responded, ""Search me."" When I asked Dereck why his girlfriend wasn't at the party yet, he said, ""Beats me. I expected her an hour ago."""
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to express one's true feelings (S)"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get off one's chest. Comment: This idiom is used when someone has long waited to express themselves. Examples: Ellen felt a lot better when she finally talked to a counselor and got the problem off her chest. Faye hasn't shared her concern about her marriage with her husband yet. I think that she should get it off her chest soon."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to spend money freely, to live luxuriously</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to live it up. Examples: Kyle and Eric saved up money for two years so that they could travel to Europe and live it up. After receiving a large inheritance from a rich aunt, I was able to live it up for years.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to energize, to make more active (also: to pick up) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to liven up. Examples: The teacher occasionally took the class on field trips just to liven things up a bit. The animals in the zoo began to liven up when evening came and the temperatures dropped. Many people have to drink coffee every morning just to pick themselves up.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to share involvement in</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to have a voice in. Examples: The new vice-president was promised that she would have a voice in developing the company's international expansion. The students are trying to have a voice in college affairs by gaining representation on administrative committees."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to register at a hotel or motel; to leave or deposit for transporting or safekeeping (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to check in. Comment: The adjective form check-in derives from this idiom. Examples: Courtney arrived in town at mid-day and promptly checked in at the Plaza Hotel. The hotel permitted an early check-in time. There were dozens of people at the airline counters waiting to check their bags in for their flights.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to pay the bill at a hotel or motel and then leave; to investigate, to examine (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to check out. Comment: The adjective form check-out derives from this idiom. Examples: The latest you should check out of the hotel is 12 noon. However, in your case, we can set a special check-out time of 2:00 P.M. The police received a call from someone claiming to have witnessed a murder. The police sent two detectives to check the call out right away.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to accept what one says as true, to believe</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to take somebody at one's word. Examples: When he offered to be responsible for the fund raiser, I took him at his word. Now he's saying that he's not available to do it. You should be careful about taking her at her word. She's been known to say one thing but to do another."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to be useful, to suit one's needs or requirements"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to serve (the/one's) purpose. Examples: I don't have a screwdriver to open this, but I think that a knife will serve the purpose. Jane prefers working to studying, so it served her purpose to drop out of school and take that job."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>very much, greatly</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>in the worst way. Examples: Jim and Claudia want to have children in the worst way. They are trying very hard to conceive. Because Umer has relatives in Turkey, he wants to visit there in the worst way.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to avoid one's responsibility, to quit"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to cop out. Comment: This idiom is an informal version of the second definition to back out (lesson 29). The noun form copout means an excuse for avoiding responsibility. Examples: Evelyn had agreed to help us with arrangements for the party, but she copped out at the last minute. I can't believe that Cindy offered such an explanation for failing to show up. What a poor copout!"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to form a line; to arrange to have, to manage to obtain (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to line up. Examples: The moviegoers lined up in front of the theater showing the most popular film of the summer. Rob is going to schedule the famous author to speak at the convention if he can line her up in time.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to get excited, angry, or flustered</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to lose one's cool. Examples: Despite the boos from some in the audience, the actors on stage never lost their cool. Although the group of skiers were in danger from an apparent avalanche, their ski guide never lost his cool."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to delay making a decision on (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to leave open. Examples: In making up the job announcement, the firm decided to leave the salary open until a qualified candidate was found. We know that the annual summer camp will be held in August, but let's leave the exact dates open for now."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to interest greatly, to excite (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to turn on. Comment: The idiom with the opposite meaning is to turn off. These idioms are used to form the nouns turnon and turnoff. Examples: Does great art turn you on? I find going to a museum and viewing classic works of art a real turnon. Going to a bar and having silly conversation with strangers really turns me off. In fact, most bar scenes are really turnoffs to me.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to lose an opportunity, to fail in some undertaking</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to miss the boat. Examples: The precious metals market was looking up several months ago, but unfortunately most investors missed the boat. Mr. Vlasic's new business went bankrupt within a short time. He really missed the boat by opening a tanning salon near the beach."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to invent, to create (also: to dream up)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to think up. Comment: This idiom is often used for an unusual or foolish thought. Examples: Who thought up the idea of painting the living room walls bright red? When asked by the teacher why she was late, the student dreamed up a plausible excuse.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to introduce an unexpected topic, causing embarrassment (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to throw (someone) a curve. Examples: The first week of class was going very well until a student threw the teacher a curve by suggesting that the textbook was too difficult. The director asked us in advance to stick to the meeting agenda and not to throw him any curves.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to create a disturbance, usually by complaining</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to make waves. Comment: This idiom is similar in meaning to the previous idiom, but the emphasis is on the aspect of complaining rather than causing embarrassment. Examples: In most companies, an employee who makes waves is not appreciated. The meeting was going smoothly until one of the participants made waves about the newly revised compensation package.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to continue as before; to conduct, to engage in; to behave in an immature manner</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to carry on. Examples: Even in the face of disaster, the inhabitants carried on as though nothing had happened. The business associates decided to carry on their discussion in the hotel bar instead of the conference room. I can't believe that John carried on so much just because his dog died. He looked depressed and cried for weeks after it happened."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>absolutely not (also: no way)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"not on your life. Comment: This idiom is used as a kind of exclamation by itself. Examples: You're asking me to invest in that poorly rated company just because you know the son of the president? Not on your life! When a friend tried to get Mark to jump out of a plane with a parachute, he immediately responded, ""No way!"""
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be extensive, to discuss much material</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to cover ground. Comment: Forms such as a lot of, too much, too little are used before the noun ground. Examples: That national commission's report on urban ghettos covers a lot of ground. Many of the recommendations are too costly to implement. In his first lecture on Greek philosophers, I thought that our professor covered too little ground."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be responsible for an office while others are gone</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to mind the store. Examples: It seems that all of our employees are taking a lunch break at the same time. I wonder who's minding the store. Lynne agreed to mind the store while the others went outside to watch the parade passing by."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to punish with full penalty, to be harsh on</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to throw the book at. Examples: Because the criminal was a repeat offender, the judge threw the book at him with heavy fines and a long prison term. My boss threw the book at me when he discovered that I had been using company time for personal business. I was severely reprimanded and forced to make up the lost time.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to say or do the wrong thing</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to put one's foot in. Comment: This idiom is used with the noun phrase one's mouth or the pronoun it. Examples: Fred really put his foot in his mouth when he called his supervisor by the wrong name. I really put my foot in it when I forgot my girlfriend's birthday and didn't buy her anything. She almost lost her cool."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become available to others</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to be up for grabs. Comment: This idiom is used when something is highly desirable to many other people. Examples: When one of the full-time contract instructors stepped down, her nice office overlooking the river was up for grabs. Did you know that Senator Stone is retiring and that her Senate seat is up for grabs?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to display one's ability in order to attract attention (S); to let others see, to expose to public view (S)"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to show off. Comment: This idiom can form the noun showoff for the first definition. Examples: Elizabeth is an excellent swimmer, but I don't like the way she shows off in front of everyone. It's very obvious that she enjoys being a showoff. Jacquie showed her large wedding ring off to all her friends."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to become familiar with routine procedures at work or school</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to learn the ropes. Examples: The job applicant didn't have much previous experience or knowledge, but she seemed intelligent enough to learn the ropes quickly. It took the new schoolteacher a year to learn the ropes regarding administrative and curricular matters."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to hope to have good results, to hope that nothing bad will happen</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to keep one's fingers crossed. Comment: This idiom reflects the way people cross their fingers to hope for good luck. Examples: Let's keep our fingers crossed that we got passing grades on that college entrance exam. Jerry kept his fingers crossed that the good weather would hold up for the picnic he was planning for the coming weekend."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to recover safely from an unpleasant or dangerous situation</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to land on one's feet. Examples: After a series of personal and professional difficulties, it's amazing that George has landed on his feet so quickly. Some young adults get into so much trouble at school that they are never able to land on their feet again. They drop out before graduating."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to distribute in large quantity (S); to speak of others in a critical manner (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to dish out. Examples: Mary's mom dished out two or three scoops of ice cream for each child at the birthday party. Larry can't seem to take any criticism of his actions but he certainly likes to dish it out."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to communicate with, to make someone understand (also: to break through to)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get through to. Comment: This idiom has the meaning of to make someone ""catch on"" (Lesson 29, eighth idiom, the first definition) Examples: Some of the students in my reading class understand English so poorly that it is difficult to get through to them. The doctors have never succeeded in breaking through to Mr. Ames, who is a silent and secretive patient."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to fulfill a promise, to be responsible</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to keep one's word. Comment: An idiom with the opposite meaning is to break one's word. Examples: Suzanne kept her word to me not to let on to others that I intend to step down next month. Thomas always intends to keep his word, but invariably the end result is that he breaks his word. He just isn't capable of being a responsible person."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to be very busy, to have too much to do (also: to be up to one's ears); to be beyond one's ability to understand"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be over one's head. Examples: I'd love to take a week off for a hiking trip, but at the moment I am over my head in work. Maybe next week when I'm only up to my ears! It was impossible for the tutor to get through to Bill about the physics problem because the subject matter was over Bill's head."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to deserve, to receive a just punishment (also: to bring upon)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to ask for. Examples: If you drink alcohol and then drive a car, you're only asking for trouble. Don't complain about your cut in salary. You asked for it by refusing to heed our repeated warnings not to be late and inefficient."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be very different from</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to be a far cry from. Examples: I enjoyed visiting Seattle, but it was a far cry from the ideal vacation spot I expected. Ned is enjoying his new job, but his responsibilities are a far cry from what he was told they would be.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>certainly, definitely, naturally (also: of course); using any possible way or method</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"by all means. Examples: If the Johnsons invite us for dinner, then by all means we have to return the invitation. Of course, we don't have to invite their children, too. In order to ensure its survival, the ailing company has to obtain an infusion of cash by all means."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to restore one's financial security, to resolve a difficult financial obligation"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to get out from under. Examples: After years of struggling to get ahead, the young couple finally got out from under their debts. The ailing company, succeeding in obtaining the necessary cash, was able to get out from under its financial burdens.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to handle a difficult situation with determination</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to take the bull by the horns. Comment: This idiom is usually used when someone has been postponing an action for some time and finally wants or needs to resolve it. Examples: After three years of faithful service, Jake decided to take the bull by the horns and ask his boss for a raise. Vic has been engaged to Laura for a long time now, and I know that he loves her. He should take the bull by the horns and ask her to marry him.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to assist, to aid, to help (also: to lend someone a hand) (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to give (someone) a hand. Examples: Would you give me a hand lifting this heavy box? When Terry's car broke down at night on the highway, no one would stop to lend her a hand."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to clap one's hands in applause, to applaud (S)"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to give (someone) a big hand. Examples: After the talented new vocalist had sung her number, the audience gave her a big hand. Should we give a big hand to each beauty contestant is as she is introduced, or should we wait until all the introductions are finished?
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to waste time, to be idle</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to goof off. Examples: Some of the workers in our office always goof off when the boss is out. On Saturday afternoons, I like to go to a movie or just goof off at home.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to answer in a rude manner, to speak disrespectfully</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to talk back to. Examples: Billy, if you talk back to me like that once more, you're going to spend the rest of the day in your room. The school principal had to reprimand the child for talking back to her teacher."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to be popular or fashionable; to be available at one's work or home"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be in. Examples: Most young people tend to want anything that is in at the time, but a few don't care about current trends. Could you please tell me when Mrs. Zachary will be in? I'd like to talk to her soon."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to be unpopular or no longer in fashion; to be away from one's work or home"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be out. Examples: These days, designer jeans are in and long skirts are out. I'm sorry, Mr. Jensen is out at the moment. Could I take a message?"
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to determine to be unacceptable, to refuse to consider</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to draw the line at. Examples: I don't mind helping him with his homework, but I draw the line at writing a term paper for him. The conference organizers tried to accommodate the needs of the various interest groups, but they drew the line at extending the conference by two days."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to disobey or ignore normal procedures or rules (also: to step out of line)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to get out of line. Examples: When a child gets out of line in that teacher's class, she uses the old-fashioned method of making the child sit in the corner of the room. Any employee who steps out of line by coming to work in an unacceptable condition will be fired."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>rehearsal, practice session</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>dry run. Examples: The college president requested a dry run of the graduation ceremony in order to ensure that all aspects went smoothly. Before the manager presented the reorganizational plans to the board of directors, he did several dry runs of his presentation.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to play music that one has heard but never read (S); to proceed without plan, to do spontaneously (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>to play by ear. Comment: The pronoun it is often used with the second definition. Examples: That pianist can play most popular music by ear. She never needs to read sheet music. My husband wanted to plan our trip carefully, but I argued that it was more fun if we played it by ear.
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>"to be in another person's position, to face the same situation as another person"</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be in (someone's) shoes. Examples: If I were in your shoes, I wouldn't take too many classes this semester. When his boss finds out about that accounting error, I wouldn't want to be in his shoes."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to remind constantly, to nag</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to keep after. Examples: Lynn always has to keep after her children about cleaning up their rooms and doing chores around the house. Lon is so forgetful that it's necessary to keep after him about every little thing."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to repair or put back in good condition (S); to arrange a date or an engagement for another person (S)</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to fix up. Examples: Instead of buying an expensive new home, we decided to buy an older home and fix it up ourselves. Since my visiting friend didn't have a date for dinner, I fixed her up with a male friend of mine. They got along very well together."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>to be victimized or cheated</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>"to be had. Examples: When the jeweler confirmed that the diamonds that the woman had purchased abroad were really fake, she exclaimed, ""I've been had!"" The angry customer complained about being overcharged at the store, asserting that this was the third time that he had been had."
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>To encourage, support, or cheer for someone or something; to wish the best for someone or something in an endeavor or activity.</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>root for
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>To be or become distracted, preoccupied, or unfocused from the present moment or the task at hand. Example: I love looking out the window on the train and just ___ for a few minutes.</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>space out
</s><break strength="none" time="2s" /></p><p><s>To question or interrogate someone intensely and relentlessly (about something).</s><break strength="none" time="4s" /><s>grill (someone) (about something)
</s></p></ns0:speak>
